We were talking about nuclear war. I
think it's something that we do have to
fear. It's very complicated. As you
said, listen, every president from when
I joined the CIA, the Israelis [music]
asked us to bomb Iran. You got to bomb
Iran. You got to bomb Iran. And every
single president said, "No." Our
position was that that would be the
start of World War II. The reason though
that Donald Trump decided to bomb Iran
was that the Israelis said, "If you
don't bomb Iran," they had never
threatened that before. It's the most
extreme right-wing government in the
history of Israel. [music] One other
thing, too, I have a friend. He was my
first boss at the CIA. In his
retirement, [music] he writes books
about these little niche foreign policy
issues. I couldn't put the book down.
And it's not just Gaza. It's Libya,
Yemen, and Iran, and Iraq. It could
[music] be a disaster. I could see the
Israelis using one on Iran, the Indians
and Pakistanis using them against
[music] each other.
>> Two questions. How realistic is that?
And two, what does the aftermath of that
look like? It's frightening. So
>> Palanteer themselves, I mean, that's a
whole another level. What kinds of
things right now are you most concerned
about?
>> I worry about the violation of our civil
liberties. It is against the law to spy
on Americans, period. [music] And that's
practically all they do where they had
to build this new facility out in Utah
that can hold every phone call, every
text message, every email from every
American for the next 500 years. And now
Palunteer is a trillion dollar company
that makes most of its money contracting
with the CIA. How about this? The
metadata from your communications is for
sale.
>> Mike Yaggley, he bought a bunch of data
in North Carolina and tracked a bunch of
phones leaving Fort Bragg, go across to
Syria for 5 days, realized they were
special forces for some undercover
operation they were doing. And he went
to the government and showed them and he
said, "I did this in my bedroom. What do
you think China's doing?" So, espionage
work in the United States.
>> We'll talk about that.
>> Yeah.
>> Hey guys, thank you so much for clicking
this video. This one with John was, as
always, awesome. the guy's the best. So,
if you have not already, please hit that
subscribe button. It is the number one
piece of help we can get to get these
videos into the algorithm. I appreciate
everyone who's been clicking these
videos, staying on and watching them for
a long time. You guys are doing awesome
with that. I'm glad you're enjoying
everything. If we can get that subscribe
button, hit a little more, this show can
really grow and we can really take off.
So, thank you guys and enjoy the
episode.
>> [music]
>> Johnny K, superstar. You get bigger and
bigger every time you come back here.
>> I was pumping gas yesterday and two guys
at different pumps asked me for selfies.
>> You love that. That's awesome.
>> I do.
>> Where is it, though?
>> I haven't. Is it under there?
>> I haven't found it yet.
>> Steve, have you seen it?
>> What's that?
your pardon, John. Pardon?
>> Where the is your pardon?
>> Oh, man. You know,
>> I've been waiting. I've been looking at
Daryl Strawberry got pardoned for three
decades ago the other day.
>> Daryl Strawberry, the the Binance guy
hurts because he didn't even apply for a
pardon. And he said on the radio the
other day, he's never met Donald Trump.
>> Yeah. Donald Trump said he has no idea
who the guy is. It's like the auto pen
ALL OVER AGAIN. DONNIE, DONNIE, BABY,
PARDON. Let's go. I will say I have very
strong deep support in the Trump
administration for a pardon. And I don't
want to say too much, but like everybody
who I have asked to help me has helped
me. And I know that
I I was told that my file is literally
on the pardon attorney's desk. So, I
just have to hope for the best.
>> Well, we got to take his little finger
there.
signed Donald J. Trump.
>> Yeah, let's go. I don't care if it's I
don't care who it is. Whatever it is
that gets it through gets the document.
You deserve it.
>> Thank you.
>> I think it's it's awesome to see you
finally getting like the widespread
recognition you've deserved for a long
time.
>> Well, you know, in in great part I have
you to thank for that. I I mentioned to
you two years ago, was it two years ago?
No, it's about a year and a half ago
that in short
order I did your podcast, Dalton Fischer
and Danny Jones,
>> one right [clears throat] after the
other over the course of maybe two
months. And for whatever reason, the
three of you together talking about
these issues
just allowed me to hit the YouTube
algorithm sweet spot.
>> Well, that's great to hear. And like I
think I think what was good is you had a
couple years there going on Danny Jo on
Danny Jones's show where I think you did
a few episodes before you did Dalton's
and mine with with Danny and you got to
go through not just your full story but
then show
>> your foreign policy chops now and how
you look at the world and I think people
got to see a nuanced view in you because
when you just hear the story you're like
okay obviously he's pissed off at CIA or
whatever but then you hear you like talk
about things and talk through issues and
the complexity of these things and your
ability to be purely analytical rather
than, you know, injecting in some of
your old annoying, you know,
>> yeah,
>> people that obviously did some horrible
things to you that could bias your
opinion. Like you do an amazing job of
just saying, well, here's A, here's B,
here's C, here's D. That's why it's E.
And I like that a lot about you.
>> Thank you. You know, when I was still in
the U director of intelligence, the
analytic uh director of the CIA, I was I
was asked to mentor this new hire, young
woman, fantastically smart. She had gone
to like Dartmouth.
No, no, no. Her brother went to
Dartmouth. She went to UVA. Very, very
bright. So, they assigned her to work on
just kind of an entry- level account. It
was uh the United Arab Emirates like
learn the politics and the economics and
then you know you can write something
whatever. So
one day Iran sent like five troops to
this little uninhabited island in the
Persian Gulf called Greater Tun. Tu NB.
It's even hard to say. There's Greater
Tun and Lesser Tun.
>> Is that where the Shai used to vacation?
>> No. No. There's nothing there. and a
couple of goats. Literally, that's it.
That's all that's on this island. So,
they moved into the tomb. There are the
tunes.
>> And uh
>> that doesn't even look real.
>> I know. It's It's terrible. And so,
we're talking about it in the morning
meeting that the Iranians invaded
greater Tun and they're occupying. It's
like, like I said, five guys just, you
know, got off the raft and okay, they
put the Iranian flag. So afterwards,
after the meeting, we went back to our
cubicles and we were talking about it
and I said, "The Iranians never never
going to leave this island." She said,
"Why not? It's, you know, with relations
with the UAE, they have so much so much
to lose." I said, "But that's the thing.
Their relations are with Dubai. The
Tunis are owned by charara, and the
Dubians don't care if the charges lose a
couple of square feet of sand. it
doesn't make any difference because
their relationship with the with the
Iranians is so strong economically that
they're willing just to overlook it.
Later in the afternoon, she came back
from wherever she had gone and she said,
"I resigned." And I was like, "What? Why
would you do that?" She was great.
>> And she said, after we talked about the
tunes, she said, "I realized I'll never
know the Middle East like you do." And
so I just quit. And she became a real
estate agent.
>> She quit because you were so smart.
>> She quit because she was like, "Too much
detail.
>> Too much detail. I I don't want to learn
it. I don't care to learn it. Nobody's
going to give a [__] about it."
>> She quit.
>> I felt so bad.
>> I really did.
>> I hope she found happiness in real
estate.
>> I hope so, too.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, that is the thing though. When
you look at even just one part of the
world and I say just one part of the
world, Middle East is a big part but
like that particular segment of the
world the number of moving pieces there
and the smallest little things
>> very complicated.
>> Isn't it unbelievable that we don't have
>> I mean obviously we've had a terrible
war going on in Gaza that maybe is
ending now. We'll talk about that in a
few minutes. But isn't it crazy that we
don't have like literal bombs going off
every day there when you consider just
how uous every relationship is.
>> You're absolutely right. And it's not
just Gaza. It It's Libya. It's Sudan,
South Sudan, Yemen. I mean, it could it
could happen pretty much anywhere
besides Syria and Iran and Iraq and
Lebanon. And it could be it could be a
disaster. Yeah. And it's not quite a
disaster. Maybe with the exception of of
Gaza and the the Sudans. M well the last
time I had you here was back in
February. So this is before
>> the whole attack on Iran
>> and what seemed to die down after that
but I don't know some of that feels like
a little bit of eerie silence. I hope
I'm wrong about that. What
>> what is the the standing there?
Obviously most of the Iranian population
doesn't support their current
leadership, but you had Israel who
clearly wants regime change. They pulled
us into it to basically like bomb
Florida, the nuclear sites,
>> and luckily like nothing kind of
happened after that and it's been pretty
quiet since. But am I missing something
there? Is is there more of that story at
this point?
>> There's there's more. Um it's very
complicated as you said a second ago,
the whole region is the the Iranian
government has practiced a policy called
strategic patience. That's what they've
described it as in the Iranian media,
strategic patience.
>> And that's manifested itself in a couple
of different ways. When when the
Israelis first attacked,
the re the Iranian response was to not
strike back. And then the Israelis
attacked a second time. And the is the
Iranian response was to send drones.
Drones move very slowly.
And so the Iranians actually warned the
Israelis in advance. We're sending
drones.
Um almost all of them were shot down.
Something like seven got through which
is a learning experience because it
shows that the Iron Dome is not perfect
even against slow motion drones.
Then the Israelis
uh you know killed
essentially the entire Iranian military
leadership just took them all out. Do
you know how they did that?
>> Very precise strikes by the way.
>> Very very precise. Not not that they
even needed to be precise because the
Israeli policy is if they want to kill
you and you're in an apartment block,
they'll take the entire city block out
and kill 2,000 people if they think they
can get you.
>> That's a policy there.
>> That's a policy. And that's why Hezbala,
for all intents and purposes, no longer
exists.
>> It will again in six months.
>> An attitude. I just want to be clear. Is
is it like an attitude that their
military has to say it, we're going to
do whatever we want. Or is it an actual
written like it's from the Israeli
political leadership?
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
So what they did is
there are hundreds of thousands of
Afghan refugees in Iran, right? They'll
never get Iranian citizenship. And
because they don't have paperwork,
they're not entitled to free medical, to
food, aid, welfare, nothing. And they're
desperate. Well, those are the guys that
the Israelis recruited. M
>> it's like we want you to stand on this
corner and every time you see this
general drive by make a note of it and
then transmit it back to us. Here's
$100.
>> They recruited thousands of these guys.
>> How would they Could you walk me through
some common
>> tactics and ways that they would recruit
someone like that? Like where are they
meeting them? How are they meeting them?
>> Sure. This is an easy recruitment that
any, you know, brand new case officer
can do. It's essentially a cold pitch.
But you're cold pitching someone who's
so desperate that they'll do anything.
>> Mhm.
>> There's no love of Iran among these
Afghans cuz the Iranians haven't given
them anything. There's no hatred of
Israel because maybe these guys don't
even know it's the Israelis that are
asking them to work. They could be
saying, "Oh, we're from the Mujahulk
MEK or we're from Iraq or we're from,
you know, Pakistan or whatever." They
don't have to say we're Israeli
intelligence officers. Those of you who
watch my show know I love walking
through New York. I never take the Uber.
I don't even like taking the subway. So,
one day last year when it was snowing a
little bit out there, I took a meeting
up on 57th Street by Central Park. To
get into the city, you take the PAT
train right in and then I'm always
walking right after that. On this
particular day though, it was literally
seting outside. So, I was wearing a nice
outfit, had the jeans rocking, my new
barber jacket. I was swagged out except
where it mattered the most, and that was
with my socks. as I decided to cut a
corner there and within 10 blocks of
starting that walk, my feet were soaked
and my $300 boots that I was really
proud of weren't holding up too great. I
got to the meeting looking like and my
feet were throbbing. Didn't go too well
after that. You know how I could have
avoided this problem? If I had some
hollow socks and just what are hollow
socks? Alpaca socks built for the field
or New York City in the snow. These are
performance-grade socks made from ultra
soft baby alpaca fibers engineered for
rugged conditions and designed to keep
your feet dry, warm, and comfortable no
matter where the day takes you. They're
also the only socks that will keep your
feet warm below freezing or also cooled
off when the temperatures hit 80°. And
they're incredibly comfortable. They're
lightweight, supportive, and most
importantly soft. And even though
they're three times warmer than wool,
they're somehow still lightweight. They
would have kept my feet dry through the
sleing streets of New York, but that's
neither here nor there. And oh yeah,
they got over 2 million pairs sold. All
made in the good old US. Once you wear
Hollow, you'll never go back. Hollow
makes all different kinds of socks as
well. And even their everyday socks are
perfect for a walk through New York or
even going on a hunting trip. Now, for a
limited time, Hollow Socks is having a
buy three, get three free sale. So, head
on over to hollowoscks.com today to
check it out. That link is in my
description below. That's
hollowoscks.com
for 50% off your order. After your
purchase, they're going to ask you where
you heard about them. If you love me,
you're going to tell them that I sent
you. Might some of these spies who are
Israeli intelligence officers, to be
clear, not be native Israelis.
>> Oh, I would suspect that almost none of
them are native Israelis.
>> Meaning they're not undercover trying to
pose like Ellie Cohen did as another.
>> Correct. Okay.
>> Correct. These are probably Iranians who
have been recruited by the Israelis
overseas or what would be even better
for the Israelis is if they are Iranian
Jews who maybe immigrated
>> and can be sent back.
>> Interesting. Okay. So, they would get a
lot of these guys easy approaches
>> like the the street type taskers easy
approaches because they they got nothing
going for them. And then what they end
up getting is, you know, jobs in these
generals houses as a tiwala, a tea boy,
or
>> that could mean a few things.
>> Sweep sweep the floor. And oftentimes it
does mean a few things. [laughter] Uh,
sweep the floors, wash the car,
whatever. Then you get the general's
cell phone number. M
>> well we know that the Israelis targeted
each individual's cell phone number so
they could track it when as it's moving
around town and fire rockets directly at
whoever happens to be holding the cell
phone. So the Iranian government then
said as a new policy no generals and no
nuclear scientist can carry cell phones.
So you know what the Israelis did
because the Israelis ended up killing
them all.
>> What' they do? They realized that the
Iranians never told the bodyguards that
they can't carry cell phones.
>> Somewhere Mike Yaggley is just hitting
the table right now. God damn it.
[laughter]
>> I will say the one the one thing that
I was really really worried would lead
to something terrible was when we
decided to bomb Iran at the Israelis
behest.
>> Yeah. Now, why would we do that, John?
Well,
there's there's a good reason why we
would do it.
Before it was done, I would have thought
it was insanity.
>> Mhm.
>> After it's been done, I think I've come
to the con conclusion that, all right,
that wasn't so bad after all,
>> really.
>> So, yeah. Um, [snorts]
listen, every president from when I
joined the CIA and George HW Bush had
just become president.
The Israelis asked us to bomb Iran.
Every single president, no matter who
the prime minister of Israel happens to
be, you got to bomb Iran. You got to
bomb Iran. You got to bomb Iran. And
every single president said, "No, we're
not bombing Iran."
I remember a couple of times when Obama,
was it Obama? Obama and Netanyahu got
into shouting matches.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah. That we didn't have an
understanding or an appreciation of what
a an existential threat Iran was or a
nuclear Iran was. You got to bomb Iran.
You got to bomb Iran. We would never
bomb Iran because the our our position
was that that would be the start of
World War II because if we bomb Iran
and maybe, you know, weakened the the
hold that the government has on the
country, then the Chinese may have to
come in or the Russians may have to come
in.
>> That was going to be my next question.
Did this just prove that this situation,
seeing as we did bomb sites there and
nothing happened, did this prove that
the Chinese and the Russians actually
don't really give a [__] about Iran, or
is that a little premature to say?
>> Maybe just a little premature, but I
would say as things stand right now,
yeah, that's that's the initial
conclusion we can draw. The reason
though, I'm told that Donald Trump
decided to bomb Iran was that the
Israelis said for the first time, if you
don't bomb Iran to take out these deep
bunkers, we're going to use nuclear
weapons.
And they had never threatened that
before. And so Trump said, "Bombing Iran
might actually save us from the start of
World War II if it keeps the Israelis
from using nuclear weapons." So
according to your source, the Israelis
told the president of the United States
that if he did not use the United States
military power to bomb the nuclear
facilities in Iran, Israel acting on its
own would use nuclear weapons.
>> Yeah.
>> Do you see why there's a problem with
that statement, John?
>> Yeah.
>> Because they've never admitted that
they've had them. That's right.
>> So you're telling me that they just
admitted to the president of the United
States that they have nuclear weapons
and we still do not have them in the
IAEA treaty? I mean, if if Israeli
nuclear whistleblowers are to be
believed, yeah, they've had them they
started working on them in the 50s. Um,
they got him around the late 60s or the
early '7s. Look at Look at Morai Venunu.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, he wasn't charged for treason
for nothing.
>> That's a guy who they hid in Rome with
the honeypot.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. 86.
>> No, he friended me on Facebook. I I
rejected the friend request. [laughter]
That's not what I asked, but okay.
>> I know. But you said was he 86? No. No.
He's alive.
>> No, no, no, no. Not 86. I think they
they got him in 198
>> Oh, in ' 86. Yeah, they got him in ' 86.
>> That's right. He friend requested you on
Facebook.
>> Yeah. And I was like, "Yeah, no, thank
you. [laughter] I I have enough problems
in my life."
Yeah. Anyway, I was on uh I was on
Pierce Morgan show a couple of months
ago and I'm on with a retired Mossad
general Danny
>> I alone.
>> I alone. Thank you.
>> So
Alan Dersitz was on.
>> Oh god.
>> And I just can't help myself sometimes
when Alan Dersowitz and I are in the
same room. I just can't help it. He's
just such
on the one hand he's a very kind and
generous man. On the other hand, when it
comes to Israel, he's he's irrational.
>> How so?
>> There's literally nothing that the
Israelis can do that's wrong. Nothing.
And he won't let you get a word out. If
he thinks that you might possibly
criticize Israel, he's going to
interrupt you until you just give up and
move on.
So, I'm arguing [laughter] I'm arguing
with him about um about whether or not
Israel spies on the United States. I
said, "Of course they spy on the United
States. They're prolific in their
espionage work in the United States,
especially as it relates to American
defense contractors, right?" And um and
Pierce
finally interrupts Dersowitz and asks
General Ayalon
um if if it's true that uh that the
Israeli spy on the United States. And he
just laughed. [laughter] He goes like
that and he says, "My position is
whatever the prime minister's position
is."
>> Okay. Well, thank you for confirming
that Israel spies on the United States.
It's the same thing with the nuclear
program. PICE came right out and asked
him, "Does Israel have nuclear weapons?"
>> What did he say?
>> And he said, "Well, the prime minister
hasn't confirmed that there are nuclear
weapons. So, I'm just going to go with
what the prime minister says,
>> but breaking news. You just reported
here today based on your source that not
only has the prime minister confirmed
it, he confirmed it to the president of
our country."
>> One other thing, too. I have a friend.
He was my first boss at the CIA. He's a
really, really great guy. He retired
years ago. And
>> John Brennan.
>> No, he's not a really great guy.
[laughter]
No,
>> we'll talk about that.
>> Yeah. So, in his retirement, he writes
books about these little niche foreign
policy issues that you might say, "Well,
who gives a [__] about that?" And then
you read the book and you can't put it
down. like US Indian relations during
the Kennedy administration. I couldn't
put the book down or some obscure little
window in the 70s of US Saudi relations,
stuff like that. So anyway, he told me
that like we all do, he sent his book
into the CIA publications review board
for clearance before he sent it to the
publisher. Um, and he said that
in all the books he's written, and he's
written at least a half a dozen,
um, they only took out um, three words,
Israeli nuclear program.
>> And I said, why?
It's it's not up to us to protect the
fact that there's an Israeli nuclear
program. We didn't classify any Israeli
nuclear program. That was improperly
classified. And he said, "Yeah, I knew
it." But then I thought, ah, it's easier
just to just to take it out.
>> I don't have any problem with I mean, if
it were up to me, no, nobody in the
world would have nukes, but seeing as
that's not the case, I don't have any
problem with them having nukes.
>> I have a problem with the fact that
every country around the world who even
might have nukes has to admit to it and
register
>> and they don't
>> and sign the nonation treaty afterwards.
>> Yeah. And it's like it's insulting to
hear that over and you see the same
reaction that you just described over
and over again. Anytime a spokesperson
of Israel is being asked about it, I
mean they sweat like a [__] in church
when you ask them about nuclear weapons.
They all know.
>> Yeah.
>> But they're like, "Yeah, no. We don't
have them." It's like, "Yeah, but
>> they all are compelled to play this
silly game."
>> Yeah.
>> It's like what?
>> Exactly.
>> But it's been 50 It's been almost 60
years. Mhm. And there are credible
reports that when the apartheid regime
fell in South Africa, they had nukes and
they gave them to the Israelis. Like why
why aren't we talking about that?
>> They gave them
>> Uhhuh.
>> I don't know anything about this.
>> Yeah.
>> Can we Google that? Oh, that was that's
been around for decades.
South African nuclear program, Israel,
something like that.
>> Interesting.
>> Mhm. I mean there there was a period in
the 70s when Argentina and Brazil were
going at it and they were both starting
to develop nukes and then they both
backed off.
Can you imagine?
>> God damn. All right. Deep's got it. So
Israel and South Africa had a secret
defense and nuclear cooperation
particularly after the 1975 Israel South
Africa agreement. While Israel
reportedly provided South Africa with
technology, knowledge, and equipment to
help with its armaments needs, there is
no conclusive evidence of significant
assistance in developing South Africa's
nuclear devices. However, documents from
2010 suggest Israel offered to sell
nuclear warheads to Africa and
[clears throat] then there's like a lot
below here as or to South Africa.
There's a lot below here. So this is
like
>> this is going forward
>> the Vela incident in 1979 satellite
>> detected a double flash of light which
is why they believed to have been a
nuclear explosion
>> a joint South African Israeli test. So
so at the least what it would appear is
that there was some cooperation on
development or at least working with the
materials which also would signify that
you have them. I mean,
>> and remember at the time the the
regime in South Africa was staunchly
pro-Israel, especially in the United
Nations. It was one of the few countries
that Israel could routinely count on.
>> That's interesting. So, back then in the
70s and 80s, you're saying?
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. I
This whole peace deal that just went
down.
>> Yeah.
>> Which is tenuous.
>> It's not a peace deal.
It's it's just a ceasefire. It doesn't
address a single one of the core issues.
Not a single one.
>> You know, stop shooting is not a peace
deal.
>> Yeah.
Do you see
like I'm rooting for it. I'm rooting for
some and obviously there's been some now
like they're fighting over what dead
bodies look like when they got like
[__] exchanged and all that. And
there's there's been some funny business
going on on both sides. But like I said,
I'm rooting for a ceasefire to continue.
Me too. And I will commend even if I
don't like the leadership of both sides,
which I don't. I will commend the people
for at least trying to do that.
>> See, that's exactly my position,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> Do you have faith that something like
this could be sustainable, though?
>> Not with the current Israeli government
in place. No. It's the most extreme
right-wing government in the history of
Israel to the point where the minister
of finance who oddly yes Motric oddly
also has jurisdiction over the West Bank
>> and Idomar Bengavir the minister of
what's his title now national security I
guess it is they both have felony
convictions for anti-Muslim hate crimes
felony convictions for hate crimes not
for you know failing to fill out an
internet form or something like that
like we have here
>> and they're in charge of the
Palestinians.
>> So, so as as long as those guys are in
in place, there's no possible way that
there can be a lasting peace. And
listen, the the bottom line, too, is
there's going to have to be an
independent Palestine. There just has to
be because the current situation's
untenable. The Israeli press has been
talking a lot over the last several
weeks, maybe over the last month, about
an idea where Israel would technically
continue to own Gaza, but the day-to-day
life of Gaza would be administered by
Saudi Arabia, which would also then
invest in things like an electrical
grid, water desalination plants, a port.
Yeah. and it would have to be um
disarmed. There would have to be no
Palestinian military. Great, right? It's
a great idea. And I've said it a couple
of times in podcasts. In 1991, I was on
my very first overseas tour in Saudi
Arabia, brand new um CIA officer. And I
was working for an ambassador who really
became legendary, Chaz Freeman. He went
on to be ambassador to China and
assistant secretary of defense. The guy
is brilliant.
Um, he he floated the idea
with the Saudis. What if we were to ask
you to build a port and an airport and a
water desalination plant and and an
electrical grid? And they said, "Yeah,
we would do it in Gaza." And then we
went to the Israelis and the Israelis
said, "Absolutely
never."
That was 1991.
And before October 7th, they only had
but 5 hours of of water every day. Then
the Israelis would shut it off. They
would have a few hours of electricity.
Then the Israelis would shut it off. The
situation's untenable because another
another October 7th is going to happen
if there's not a sort of a pressure
release valve. You know what was it
Martin Luther King said? Never
underestimate a man's desire to be free.
>> Yeah. Well, they've got to concede
something.
>> Did you know that one in eight Americans
are currently prescribed anti-anxiety
medications? It is a quiet epidemic that
is sweeping the West right now. And
people who start on these medications
have a very hard time quitting.
Recovering from benzoipene addiction or
alcohol addiction is essentially like
recovering from brain damage. But what
if I told you that a legal mushroom that
has been weirdly embedded into our
culture is helping people to finally get
off these GABAurgic substances? I'm
talking about ammonita muscaria, the
little red top mushroom with the white
dots that's depicted in Alice in
Wonderland and Mario. This is a legal
mushroom to buy, possess, and sell in
every state except Louisiana, and
thousands of people are currently using
it to get off benzoipines and alcohol.
This mushroom isn't always for people
looking to quit their anti-anxiety
medications. Many people are tapping
into its power as a natural neutropic
for focus during studies and work, a
non-addictive alcohol replacement at
parties, a dream enhancing tool for
vivid nights, and even a gentle aid for
pain recovery. Amenita can do a lot more
than help you quit gabaurgics. And it's
been hiding in plain sight this whole
time. For years, there was a massive gap
in the market where nobody in the United
States was reliably importing this
mushroom. That's where Amanara comes in,
providing you with the highest quality
raw Amanita and consumerready Amanita
products at a price that you can afford.
So use Amanara to help find your Harmony
today and go to www.antara.com/go/julen.
That link is in my description below.
When you check out, make sure you use
code jd22 for 22% off your order. That's
www.antara.com/go/ amara.com/go/julian
code JD22. Much love. I've actually
never thought about not what you just
said, but like an idea I'm getting from
that and I'm just thinking about this
live and out loud. So, this might be the
dumbest thing I've ever said or it could
be like something that's worth kicking
around.
>> What obviously Palestinians and Saudi
Arabians are are are different. It's
they're different groups of people.
Yeah. But they're both a part of the
Arab population, if you will.
>> Correct.
>> What if like a two-state solution
involved
Palestine becoming a part of Saudi
Arabia?
My off the top of my head, my guess is
the Saudis would find that workable and
the Israelis wouldn't. The is but the
isra the Saudis and Israelis are
starting to get somewhat along now.
>> Yes. But we should also not under
underestimate the Israelis desire for a
biblical greater Israel. Yes. And to
give away land is not in the Israeli
playbook.
>> And that's that's the problem here cuz
like
>> you saw the day after the ceasefire,
Hamas started executing people in the
streets because they're they're a
terrorist group and that's what they do.
They they're they're evil and they're
going to do stuff like that.
They exist because there's a vacuum in a
place that's not allowed to have a
military, not allowed to have a state
government run government, not allowed
to economically vive for itself. It's
locked basically on all four borders.
We've gone through that at nauseium
before, you and I, on podcast.
>> What do you expect there to be?
>> Exactly. Exactly right. And it's even
more complicated than that. In 1990,
Iraq invaded Kuwait. Right. We
[clears throat] put together one of the
greatest albeit temporary military
alliances
in you know since the second world war
[snorts]
and um we went to the Palestinians and
said you better be on the right side of
this thing right. We also said the same
thing at the at the time the the United
Nations Security Council happened to
include Cuba and Yemen as two of the
states. So, we weren't sure what they
were going to do, which way they were
going to vote. It didn't matter because
they didn't have veto power anyway. But
we wanted as united an international
front as we could come up with. And we
went to the Palestinians all the way to
the top to Yaser Arafat and said, "You
better be on the right side of this."
And they jumped in with uh Saddam
Hussein.
>> The thing is is half the population of
Kuwait was Palestinian
>> and Bahrain and Qatar and the United
Arab Emirates and Saudi Arabia. Well,
Saudi Arabia was half half the
population was Yemeni. And so when
Arafat took a position
um
well first Saudi Arabia expelled
literally every Yemen I flew into Yemen
as that was happening uh in in very
early it was like February or March of
1991.
I flew from Jedha and as you're coming
into Sana,
>> I mean for 15 minutes before you you get
to the airport, all you could see were
people living in cardboard boxes or tin,
you know, leantos and shanties. They had
expelled half the population of Yemen
>> back into Yemen where there was no food
and no water, no work in the first
place. the I I was in Kuwait. I've
mentioned before on liberation day we
went in with the Marines and um
a a senior Kuwaiti prince told me
and I reported it at the embassy team
meeting. The ambassador I still remember
the ambassador just shaking his head
like oh my god. The senior Kuwaiti
prince told me in a year there will be
no Palestinians in Kuwait. None.
>> What was his reasoning?
>> They had sided with the Iraqis. They
were all traders and they had to pay for
it. So the problem with that is the
Palestinians are the middle class of the
Middle East. They're the professors, the
doctors, the lawyers, the engineers, the
the public school teachers. They're the
ones that make the economy run. You want
Palestinians. They're all educated. You
want them in your country until their
leadership turns on you. M
>> and so they started replacing them with
Filipinos and Thai and Pakistanis, lots
of Egyptians because the Egyptians are
well educated too. So you have lots of
Egyptian engineers. All the pilots at
Gulf Air for example, Kuwait Airways
were all Egyptians after that and the
Palestinians were left out on their
ears. Where do you go? You can't go back
to your country because you have no
country. So what do you do? It was the
stupidest decision that Yaser Arafat
ever made in his life. Like this was an
easy win. You know,
>> that's what I'm saying. These are the
types of leaders that they've had
>> over the last 75 plus years who
>> are these upstart Blackhand
organizations, not run by the best
people at all,
>> you know? And like that's the thing like
when the Israelis will say like, "Oh,
Yaser Arafat was a terrorist." That you
could disagree with them. They have a
case there.
>> Sure. and so was Manakim and you know
that and they you can move on from that
and win the Nobel Peace Prize for what
that's worth. I'm sorry. Um two other
issues
>> that that make this more complicated.
Egypt.
Okay. The the
Palestinians desperately want the Rafa
border crossing open. Okay. The
Egyptians are not going to open the Rafa
border crossing. They're just not.
>> Why? because it'll result in a flood of
Palestinians leaving Gaza and entering
Egypt. And the Egyptians can barely feed
their own people
>> or provide work for their own people.
They're like 120 million Egyptians. And
what they're going to have to worry
about another two million Palestinians
and feed and clothe and employ them.
They can't do it,
>> right?
>> They just can't do it. The other one is
Jordan.
Most people now are too young to
remember that in 1968,
the Jordanian military was literally
fighting the Palestinians on the steps
of the palace as Black September, the
Palestinian group, was trying to to
murder King Hussein and his family and
take over Jordan and make it Palestine.
>> Y
>> Well, they have long memories in Jordan.
Yeah. Half the population is Palestinian
because they're the children, the
grandchildren, the great-grandchildren
of 1948 refugees.
>> So is half the royal couple.
>> And so is half the royal couple.
Absolutely true. Um but the thing is
they'll never be fully Jordanian.
In fact, Jordanians have, you know,
carry a green passport and if you're
Palestinian bord in in Jordan, you carry
a black passport.
>> So you don't even get first class
rights.
So, it's very complicated. Like, people
say the right things, governments in the
Middle East say the right things about
Palestinians, but when it comes time to
put their money where their mouths are,
not a whole lot gets done.
>> So, putting Jordan aside for a second,
because there's another layer there that
maybe we can come back to that you and I
have talked about before.
One argument
that the Israelis have made over the
years that I think really does have some
weight to it is that a lot of the Middle
East and the Arab countries don't really
give a [__] about the Palestinians.
They're just a useful, you know, tool of
propaganda to be able to say, "Oh, look
what the Israelis are doing." But they
don't really care about the people. And
I would argue even today, even after the
last two years and what we've seen in
some cases, I I think they're right
about that. I think so too. And I think
that's one of the reasons why the
Abraham Accords have been so uh popular
and so wellreceived around the Middle
East. Just in the last week, Kazakhstan
of all places joined the the Abraham
Accords
>> to include
Bahrain, the United Arab Emirates, you
know, Tunisia, Morocco, Sudan. I may be
missing one or two. And the the crown
jewel is going to be Saudi Arabia. And I
think eventually Saudi Arabia joins as
well
>> because the bottom line is it'll be good
for the Saudi economy. and uh and they
don't really care about the Palestinians
so terribly much.
>> There's been obviously MBS is where it
starts and ends with the book in Saudi
Arabia% but there's been some mixed
messaging from the extended royal family
when they talk publicly about Israel
Palestine. There's some who are clearly
supporting Israel and others who are
like no we're we need to figure out Gaza
here. What they're doing to the
Palestinians is wrong.
>> Remember that the king's title is not
just king Malik. It is king [snorts] and
custodian of the two holy mosques.
>> So he has to have pristine Islamic
credentials as well.
>> None of them do. I mean King Fed took it
on the chin for you know coming here
when Reagan was president and you know
there there were pictures from the
Associated Press of him toasting Reagan
with a glass of wine. You're not
supposed to drink wine. They were ready
to overthrow the government. They were
so upset.
>> But um
>> but NBS is a is a unique case. Um, he's
not afraid to kill people who he thinks
are going to stand in his way, including
people named
>> al-Soud.
>> Uh, and
well, I I'll tell you, uh, Julian, I I
went to Saudi Arabia in 2021
or two. I went I went to cover uh
Biden's trip there.
>> Oh, you were covering it? Yeah, I was
there in 2022, I think. It was the
summer of 2022. And I hadn't been back
to Saudi Arabia since like 1996,
right? So, it had been a long time since
I had been in Saudi Arabia. And I didn't
recognize the place.
>> Women driving. I was like, "Oh my god."
[laughter]
Windows down, music blasting, their
movie theaters. I'm like, "What
happened?" [laughter]
And here I've been yelling about the
Saudis being, you know, from the stone
age and it's just not true under NBS,
his murderous, you know, uh, Jackal and
Hyde.
>> Little murder for
trade.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Um, when he said he was going to he was
going to bring Saudi Arabia into the
21st century, he meant it.
>> He did. He and it happened quickly.
[snorts]
>> You know, I remember bowling I I went I
when I was living there in '91, I went
bowling at the Hilton, right? It was a
group of us from the embassy. There was
a there was a two-lane bowling alley on
the roof of the Hilton and um they had
to put a big uh curtain in between
[clears throat] us. It was a curtain
that was hanging from the uh from the
ceiling. So the men bowled on one side
and the women bowled on the other side
and we could hear each other but we were
forbidden from seeing each other
>> like your own women.
>> Yeah. From the embassy. Cuz you know if
men and women bold together the next
thing you know they're going to be
having sex in the bowling lane.
>> Wouldn't want that.
>> Of course.
>> Wouldn't want that. So I say, "Hey,
look, you know, they're moving up to the
modern day."
>> Yeah. Now it's like, you know, they're
blasting Tupac from the car and women
driving. They're hanging out of the
window. Woo! It's like I remember
standing at the window of my hotel like
like I was in the Twilight Zone.
>> That's So they get to relive the '9s,
too, while they're getting their pop
culture. Seriously, good time to be
alive. Good for them.
>> Hey guys, if you haven't already
subscribed, please hit that subscribe
button. It's a huge, huge help. Thank
you. Do you
going over the the whole Middle East
though? May maybe we should go back to
Jordan for a sec just because I I said I
put a pin in that. You and I have talked
about this before, but like the
Jordanian king who I actually kind of
like. He's very very interesting guy.
>> Yeah, he's he's the right leader for
that country.
>> He when you look at his foreign policy
predictions over the last 25 years, I
mean every people should just listen to
that guy. Like he's almost never wrong.
Oh, I would go so far as to say of
everybody in the region or everybody who
studies the region, no one knows as much
as King Abdullah.
>> I think you have a good argument there.
I mean, he's he's this guy who never
wanted the job. He's been western
educated as well.
>> Never expected to get the job.
>> Never expected to get it. His dad was
dying and said, "It's going to be you,
not the other son." He was like, "What?"
No, no, it was it was the king's brother
>> that was the crown prince and they had
>> I thought he was getting skipped over
and it was going to be the oldest son
that was going to get it and then he
said, "No, I'm going to give it to the
second son."
>> No, no, he is. He's the oldest.
>> He is?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Uh the brother
got a little too big for his britches.
The King Hussein had cancer. Yeah.
>> And his death was a slow one. And he was
universally loved.
>> My wife cried when he died. We were
stationed in Athens at the time. I was
like, "Your second wife."
>> My first wife.
>> First wife.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh he was universally loved. And um
his death was a slow one. And so as he
was approaching death, the crown prince
decided, "I'm going to start making some
preliminary changes. I'm going to make
this change and that change. I'm going
to restaff the Joint Chiefs of Staff."
And and King Hussein's like, "Whoa, I'm
not even dead yet. We're not going to do
this. You're fired. my son uh Abdullah
is going to be the crown prince. And
Abdullah's like, "What? I never wanted
to be crown prince." Next thing you
know, he's crown prince. And then his
dad dies a couple months later.
>> Yeah. [snorts] Now, he I've talked about
this before with you, but
>> he was asked at some conference
in the weeks after October 7th, 2023.
Among many questions, he was being
obviously asked about the about the
conflict that was going on and and what
this looked like and all that. But then
he of course was asked, "Will you accept
Palestinian refugees?" And he said, "I'm
glad you asked that question."
And I will not. Not because I don't want
them, not because I don't like them. My
wife is Palestinian. That's not the
issue here. If I do accept them though,
I will give Israel exactly what they
want. They will be able to ethnically
cleanse the whole area. They'll go to
countries like mine, and the problem
will be taken care of. And I then fast
forwarded and saw a press conference
with him and Trump in the Oval Office
when Trump got back in here where
Trump's talking about sending some
Palestinians in there and you just see
the king sitting there like, "God damn
it."
>> Yep. Not going to happen. It's just not.
And you know, if if Donald Trump's idea
to develop
uh Gaza and make it better than Monte
Carlo, which is what he said, go with
God. The Palestinians could use the
influx of cash.
Sure, make it better than Monte Carlo. I
think that would be a wonderful thing.
>> I don't think he has them in mind
running it, though.
>> No. So,
>> he doesn't. No, he never did.
>> He never did. And that's like, you know,
that's the thing you you talk about it
as the obvious point that like you got
to be able to give people a state. There
has been so much hatred built up on both
sides over all these years since, you
know, Israel began to exist and all that
that the unfortunate reality to me is
that if you were actually as a world
going to commit to a two-state solution,
you would need to accept the fact that
you're going to have what's called the
bloody generation,
>> which means, all right, let's say
tomorrow I put in a two-state solution.
For the next 20 to 25 years, I'm going
to have all the young blood of people
who grew up hating each other, wanting
to kill each other, and completely
disagreeing with this solution. And
every time there's some sort of attack
from one side or the other, instead of
being like, "Well, nope, can't do a
two-state solution. War, someone
attacked the other one, and that's it."
You have to be able to say, "No, we're
going to keep the two-state solution,
and it's not going to be war." Which
goes against every human guarantee it.
They have to guarantee peace. How
possible is that even remotely possible?
>> It's
possible, I suppose. I mean, pretty much
anything can be negotiated if if the two
sides [snorts] are serious enough about
it. Let me let me
give you an example of of why I think
what you said just now can be overcome.
Hm. Um, I was having I was having lunch
one day with a Greek diplomat uh at this
outdoor cafe in DC and some guy comes up
and and uh he says, "Hey, you know,
Aphrodite or whatever her name, I think
her name was Aphrodite. How are you?"
She gets up, "Oh, how are you?" And I
was like, "Ok Turkish name." She gets up
and kisses this guy on both cheeks and
uh he introduces himself. I say hi. I
shake his hand. He walks away. And I
asked her, "What the [__] was that all
about? You kiss a Turk."
And she said, "Only you Greek Americans
have that position on the Turks. We have
to live with them." And after all these
centuries of fighting, we just decided
it's better to be nice.
>> Interesting.
>> And I've noticed that I mean leader to
leader, sure, there are problems, right?
Or or intelligence service to
intelligence service, even military to
military sometimes. But on the on the
people-to-people level,
they really don't have any problems.
>> That's interesting. Some of my buddies
in Greece though, I'm thinking about
this. They they all did serve in the
military though.
>> Yeah, mine too. In fact, I was I took my
son to Greece in January. We're at my
cousin's house. We're from the island of
Roads, which is considered a border
island because I mean, you can hear the
Turks playing their music at night.
That's how close it is. And um we're in
we're in a house, my cousin Chris's
house that's been in my family for 175
years. So he he's the recipient. Wow.
>> Of the of the house. So we're sitting in
there and I kind of look past him and I
said, "Chris,
is that a machine gun?" And he said,
"Yeah." I said, "Why do you have a
machine gun? How do you have a machine
gun?" And he says, "John, I'm former
special forces. You see how close these
Turks are to us? [laughter] They could
swim here by the time I get to the gun."
>> He said, 'We have to protect ourselves
somehow. That is one thing. So, that
aside,
>> you know, on the mainland, they don't
really care so much.
>> Mhm. [clears throat]
>> That's good.
>> Yeah, it's good.
>> With that's a long way of saying the
Palestinians and the Israelis can get
there someday. And you know, people say
all the time, too, that there can't be a
an independent Palestine. It's just
never going to happen. I went to school
with this kid, Reheis Pescurius. I still
remember his name. Shout out to Remis
Pescurius.
>> What a name.
>> Yeah, he's Lithuanian. And um we went to
GW together and he used to he was a
militant Lithuanian. He used to say,
"Someday Lithuania will be free." And we
were like, "Dude, you have to get past
this free Lithuania thing. the Soviets
are never gonna allow Lithuania to be
free. [clears throat] And like six years
later,
>> yeah,
>> there's a free Lithuania. So, you never
know. You know, when an issue is ripe,
there's nothing you can do to stop it.
>> I like your optimism. [laughter] I I
hope that's the case. I think in this
particular situation, because you also
have religion
>> Yeah.
>> in the middle of it.
>> See, this is a very important beef that
I have. I hope you'll let me vent for a
Oh, you can do whatever you want, John.
>> One of the biggest problems that we have
in this entire Israel Palestine
situation is the problem of Christian
Zionists,
most of whom are American evangelical
Christians. [gasps]
Palestine used to be 10% Christian. It's
now more like two or 3% Christian. And
most of those Christians have moved to
the United States. Well, evangelical
support for the Israeli government has
resulted in an ethnic cleansing and the
and the destruction of Christian
communities in in historic Palestine.
So, what side are you on? Are you trying
to save Christianity or are you trying
to destroy Christianity? Because you're
destroying it right now. And listen, and
I'm going to take a lot of [__] in your
comment section for saying this, but
listen, if your religion was created in
somebody's basement in the 1800s, I
don't want to hear your position on
Israel and Palestine. I don't find it
valid.
>> Yeah. I I think that there's been people
overlooking things. And I I think that
the saddest part of this whole struggle
is that in society we seem to have an
inability to separate people from their
governments just at the at the simplest
level. I mean you spelled it out before.
You're like Netanyahu's government wins
with [__] 27% of the vote. It's all
the Orthodox Jews over there.
>> Exactly. You know, there was a
borderline they were very close to civil
war in the summer before October 7th,
which is quite interesting timing by the
way, where Netanyahu seized control of
the judiciary 5 weeks before
they were ra people were in the streets.
We were we were seeing we were seeing
demonstrations especially in in Tel Aviv
and Hifa that were unprecedented in
scale. He was this close to being
overthrown and having to call new
elections.
>> That's the thing, John. It's like
we've
on every angle of this, we've sacrificed
humanity, right? We've watched thousands
of people be killed and we fight about
it over tweets. Let's call it what it
is. Yeah, I'm guilty. I mean, I don't
fight a lot on Twitter, but like I'm
watching these tweets, too. So, I'm
guilty of it just like everyone else.
And we also
generalize all the people involved. And
these are such
this is such a nuance situation when it
comes to the people involved and who it
is. And like you've now seen, you know,
I have so many Jewish friends in America
who don't [__] with what Israel is doing
at all.
>> And yet they get dragged into this cuz
it's like, you know,
>> it's true. It leads to anti-semitism. I
was having lunch in New York. I'm gonna
say the the weather was nice, so it must
have been like May or June sitting with
a buddy of mine at an outside uh cafe.
And he happens to be Jewish.
>> He's not
Zionist or fist in the air. He just
happens to be Jewish. So, we're talking
about this uh about October 7th and the
war, about Israel's response to October
7th. and he said, "As a Jew, I really
fear that Israel's heavy hand is going
to result in increases in anti-semitism,
especially in the United States." Well,
there were these two women sitting next
to us, both in their 80s, they told us
later,
>> and one of them finally said, "Excuse
me, but I couldn't help but to overhear
your conversation."
She, the one said, "We're both Jewish,
too, and we have the same fears. We are
seeing an increase in anti-semitism,
especially in New York,
>> but it's because of the Israeli
government's actions.
>> Otherwise, most people wouldn't pay any
attention
>> to what's going on in in Israel.
>> Wouldn't care. And and that's
>> wouldn't register with them.
>> That's what's so like sometimes it feels
like society is just being manipulated
to break at all times. I've I've for a
long time had this quote. I'm sure
someone else came up with it at some
point. I've just never cared to Google
it. But, you know, at least it sounded
smart the first time I said it. A
divided society is a compliant society.
And when you can divide people on one or
two really emotional issues, you know,
four or five years ago it was COVID and
the [__] vaccine and now it's Israel
Palestine, you can distract from
everything else that you don't want them
to know about or you don't want them to
focus on. And it's like, you know, I
talk with people who are very hardcore
Zionist and I talk to people who are
very hardcore anti-ionist. And the
commonalities I see in those
conversations is that they will each
make a separate point that is like,
"Yes, agree 100%."
>> But they're pointing at a problem that's
over here. Yeah. And I'm like,
>> "Right,
>> yes, I agree with you. Now come back
here. See how it works this way too,
right here at home." And they're like,
"Well, no, not whenever it comes to
their issue, whatever it is, they're
unwilling to see it there, but they'll
see it everywhere else." And I'm like,
"Guys, if we're, especially from an
American perspective, this is my issue
with this. You should be worried about
the interests of Americans first and
what's going on here first. It doesn't
mean separate from the world. It doesn't
mean become an isolationist, but like
you should worry about what are the
downstream effects here." So if China,
Qatar, Iran, and Israel are all doing
propaganda campaigns that involve body
counts in the United States, I don't
make a distinction between any of them.
It's all the same thing. Why is it so
hard for you Zionist and you anti-ionist
to see you only see these three and you
only see that one?
>> It's the same [__]
>> It's the same thing.
>> Yeah, I couldn't agree more. You know,
one of the things too that has been a
surprise for me, even if it shouldn't be
a surprise is is the difficulty that
Americans have in even listening to
people who with whom they disagree.
>> Yeah.
growing up
my just like on my dad's side for an
examp as an example when my dad's
parents came to the United States my my
grandmother was a royalist right she
supported the Greek royal family which
wasn't Greek it was Danish and the king
couldn't even speak Greek so he was
overthrown
which he deserved to be
so [laughter]
so my grandfather was a was a republic
Repan with a small R. Um he supported
the establishment of of the Hellenic
Republic. Um
and um and that's what the Greeks have
now. Politically they both somehow
became Democrats. On my mom's side, my
grandparents didn't give two shits about
politics in Greece and they became
Republicans and most of their kids were
Republicans. My mom was a Democrat, but
my uncles voted for Wallace in ' 68 very
very happily.
>> And I remember my I won't even say it
because yeah, it's it involves some not
very nice words, but uh they voted for
Wallace, my two uncles, and um and then
I I still remember being a little kid
and seeing the Nixon now buttons that
they that they had on. So, it just never
occurred to me that there were people
out there who wouldn't speak to other
people just because they believe in one
thing or don't believe in another. My
best friends from high school, best
friends. I mean, we're all in each
other's weddings. We're godfathers to
each other's kids.
Dave McCrack and Dave's passed away, but
Dave was a was a Republican, Gary Senko
Republican, Guy Cabellis a Democrat, and
Russ Kleta a Democrat. And it never
mattered to any of us. And I just don't,
you know, people say all the time, I
can't believe you would go on Fox News.
Why wouldn't I go on Fox News? I have a
position on an issue like John Brennan.
It happens to fit in with Fox News's
editorial position,
but maybe I can educate a Fox News
viewer.
>> Sure.
>> If I go on tonight and I have my 20
seconds to speak my piece.
>> Yeah. I think I think it's very
deliberate from they whoever they
>> Yeah. They they don't want us to talk to
one another.
>> They don't want us to do it.
>> Mhm.
>> Like for example, I'm sorry to interrupt
you. I'm fascinated by this fissure that
we're seeing right now uh among
conservatives about Tucker Carlson's
decision to interview Nick Fuentes.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Why wouldn't you interview Nick
Fuentes? If you think he's a turd with
with repulsive positions, then expose
him as a turd with repulsive positions,
don't say, "Oh my god, I can never talk
to him." No, writing him off can't talk
to him. Talk to him and let him destroy
himself with his repulsive positions.
But this idea now, well, they have to
cut off Tucker. He's no good anymore.
And oh, the head of the Heritage
Foundation said something nice about
him, so now he has to resign. It's like,
what's wrong with you people?
Yeah, I think that part I think that
part's crazy. I I do
>> I would love to get your thoughts on
this though because I look at this
whole Tucker situation.
It's very fascinating to me watching
watching it happen because I think
you're seeing a lot of laws of human
nature play out. And
>> what I mean by that is
>> Tucker raised some points a year ago,
year and a half ago, whatever that were
valid points.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Apolitical in a lot of ways. We're
talking foreign policy, things going on
in the Middle East, asking
>> Yes.
>> very valid questions.
>> And he's very wellinformed.
>> He is wellinformed. And he got viciously
attacked
>> by people for it who sought to destroy
him. Yes. And silence him. And one thing
about Tucker is he's an emotional guy.
Takes one to no one, you know. And so he
reacts to those things and he fights
fire with fire. And then the fire gets
bigger and the fire gets bigger and the
fire gets bigger and pretty soon, you
know,
you end up saying things just to set
each other off. And I I think we've gone
far past that point. I thought the
attacks on him, calling him anti-Semitic
were [__]
anti-semitic. See, but this is the
thing. This is where that propaganda
that you talked about a few minutes ago
um enters in. It is that many Americans
have been convinced that if you are
anti-Netanyahu
or if you are opposed to the present
policies of the current Israeli
government, you are anti-Semitic. In
fact, a an Israeli friend of mine, a
close Israeli friend of mine who served
in the IDF and everything told me that
they're actually taught to do that at
school. That any criticism of Israel,
they're supposed to label as
anti-Semitic so that people back off and
people generally do back off.
>> So, I can criticize any government
around the world, even China now.
Remember when that was a thing? You were
racist if you criticized China. Now,
they love you criticizing China, right?
Like you can criticize any country
around the world and it's not racist
when you criticize their government,
>> but when you criticize this one, it's
racist.
>> Yes,
>> that's wrong. And you know, here's the
thing about Tucker and Fuentes because I
I am a free speech absolutist, right?
>> And I think everyone should be allowed
to talk. I think Nick Fuentes,
I wildly disagree with who he is as a
person, everything.
>> But he's got a right to say whatever he
wants to say.
>> Free speech. He has a right to say what
he wants to say.
>> 100% agree.
>> The question here, John,
>> is if people just look at it on just
this situation. Don't look at the whole
buildup to it, which is absolutely
relevant, but just look at it in this
situation with Tucker.
>> People are looking at Tucker going,
why are you using your platform to talk
to a guy like that? And I want to be
careful how I say this as someone who
has a platform and talks to people from
all ends of the spectrum.
[sighs]
I think that when you do something like
that, when you're Tucker Carlson,
you are doing it and giving your enemies
exactly what they want.
Yeah, I can see that. I can see that.
But on the other hand, too, look at this
way. He does how many of these a week?
Um, one, two, three, I don't even know.
>> A lot, I'm sure.
>> A lot. Um, this is just another one in a
long line of guests.
>> He's going to have somebody on that's
going to be the exact opposite. [snorts]
>> Uh, he's going to have on um the nun
from uh Jerusalem, George
Stephanopoulos's sister. [laughter]
>> Is that actually his sister?
>> You know, I actually Googled it and it
said that she is. I don't know. I don't
see any kind of family resemblance. And
you know, funny little funny little
small world tidbit. George
Stephanopoulos's grandfather was my
parish priest when I was a little kid
and he baptized me and I remember George
from Sunday school. He was a year two
older than I was. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Small world.
>> Small world. Yeah.
>> But uh and actually his dad married my
brother and his first wife.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. He was a priest here at the Holy
Trinity Cathedral in New York.
>> Oh, you Greeks.
>> We all stick together.
>> Yeah. We're all paria. We all enjoy each
other's company. So anyway, um for me
personally, I wouldn't have invited um
Nick Fuentes just because I don't think
I would have much to say to somebody
like Nick Fuentes. But Tucker feels
liberated since he left Fox News. He
feels unencumbered
by corporate structures and policies and
he just decided that he was going to
have on anybody who he thought would
give him two or three hours of
interesting conversation. Yeah. And I
also because I'm also not a believer in
bringing someone in there just to stick
them through the ringer and you know CBS
News, right? Which is why I wouldn't
talk with them
>> except for Ted Cruz.
>> That was pretty funny.
>> That was funny.
>> That was kind of funny. Apac Ted.
>> Yeah. Apac Ted.
>> By the way, by the [laughter] way,
trivia question. Who would who did Alan
Dersitz say was the most talented law
student he ever had?
>> Oh, it has to be Ted.
>> Yeah. I always thought that was
interesting. You know, so many people
believed that Ted was destined for the
Supreme Court, not for Capitol Hill.
>> He was a real thinker at Harvard Law
School.
>> Oh, he's a Listen, for as much as he got
bodybagged and thrown down the [__]
river. See the river sticks by Tucker
Carlson [snorts] right there? Like,
>> he's a very smart guy.
>> Very smart.
>> Very smart guy.
>> He was wrong on those issues, which is
why Tucker beat him about the head and
face.
>> It was funny. Uh, who I'd like to see
next is Lindsey Graham.
[laughter]
>> It will never happen. We'll see if he
even survives this primary.
>> Yeah, I I I hope not. I don't know how
that guy's ever survived any election in
that state.
>> But like maybe people wanted to see and
and I actually I haven't watched the
Tucker Fuentes sit down yet, so I really
can't comment on it. So I I don't want
to.
>> It was a normal Tucker interview. It was
a normal conversation and Tucker fully
freely disagreed with a lot of what he
had to say.
>> All right. So,
>> but let him speak.
>> Let him speak. The the thing that I
think about here because of how hot
button the issue is and how much there
is
pieces of information that can be used
to label going on. Like let's look at
who you might look at as as people that
are cringe and annoying, which might be
like the hardest core Zionists who
anything that they don't like is labeled
anti-Semitic, which is a woke tactic. It
is
>> for them to use.
If I were those people,
what would I want Tucker Carlson to do?
>> I would want him to interview Nick
Fuentes. because now all I got to do is
post that screenshot of that regardless
of context, regardless of intention,
regardless of what it is. And it's like
I read this thing recently. I was
talking about it with Mike Ritland, but
I recently read that in at the height of
the Roman Empire's power when the
generals would be at war in the midst of
battle and the night before or the
morning of a battle, they'd be gathered
in their tent, you know, the three to
five highest ranking generals to make a
decision. They would have this exercise
where they would ask themselves, if we
were our worst enemy right now, meaning
the guys across the battlefield who are
going to fight us, if we were our worst
enemy right now, what decision would we
want us to make?
>> That's brilliant. Yeah.
>> And they would think of it. It would
always land on like the most emotional
[__] you eye for an eye type decision.
They'd be like, okay, let's do the
opposite of that.
>> And they won again and again and again
and again. And it is so easy now to get
angry at pe. It's human nature to get
angry at people who attack you
incessantly with lies and propaganda and
[__] You want to punch these
people. I'm from New Jersey, trust me.
Like I would not deal with it well.
Yeah.
>> But you got to like go into a room,
scream into a pillow,
>> and think, what am I going to do with
this so that I can rise above it? Do I
want to be more Malcolm X or do I want
to be more Martin Luther King? All due
respect to Malcolm X, obviously had
certain stances and whatever. Very
interesting guy in history. The more
effective one was Martin Luther King and
he deserves all the credit in the world
for that because he rose above stuff at
the in the hardest way
>> as well. And it's like I get it.
Everyone has a right to speak. I'm not
saying don't go speak with Nick Fuentes
or something like that, but when you do
that, you have now opened yourself up to
a whole new round of attacks that could
have
>> I agree
>> appeared credibility.
>> I agree. The reason why I wouldn't have
had Nick Fuentes, well, it's
severalfold. Um,
and you know, a part of this is
obviously my own bias. I see him as just
some kid. He's just some loudmouth kid.
Mhm.
>> And
many of his positions have been
definitively debunked
by historians over the years. I mean,
there are still people alive who
liberated Dahal, for example,
>> or Bergen Bellson or whatever. And um
[snorts]
I just don't see how it's possible that
his base of support grows from what it
is. And what it is is a bunch of angry
white guys in their 20s.
So I I just don't see what good it would
do me to interview somebody like him.
That's why I wouldn't do it.
>> He's if you look at the it at it
objectively just like 30,000 foot view
of why
>> he's risen or whatever it is.
>> Obviously he is a very good speaker.
>> He is
>> he's very bright.
>> He's very bright for sure. He has a
sense of humor as well. He can talk to
the camera for hours.
>> Disarming actually.
>> Yes.
>> That's the first time I ever saw him at
any length in an interview and I was
like, oh, he's he's actually a likable
guy at first glance.
>> At first glance.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, there's ways like if you
wanted to look at it like, oh, the wolf
coming in the hen house or something.
That's how it happens when you have
those other talents. But when society
gets to a point, this is just my macro
theory on it, but
>> you look at a middle class that has been
legislated away economically like that
in a graph since the beginning of the
1980s.
>> That's right.
>> And you see chaos and chaos and chaos
and chaos and chaos and lack of hope and
people who are upset about their lives.
They're carrying around college debt cuz
they were sold a system when they were
15 and had no [__] idea what it
meant.
>> Mhm. You turn that emotion in somewhere
and you turn it in to point it at the
fingers of the elite people regardless
of where they stand that you don't like.
And when you have someone like Nick
Fuentes who regardless of how he does it
or what he says speaks to that kind of
yes crowd and does it very effectively.
That is how you get something like that
to happen. And also this needs to be
said because we've seen this on every
side of all these issues whether you're
pro or antie. Pick your favorite issue
here. There are massive propaganda bot
campaigns supporting both sides.
>> You're absolutely right.
>> Yes. Which is also dangerous and
completely unregulated.
>> What do we do about that?
>> I don't know. Can you do anything about
it? Like you can pass a law saying, you
know, no more about no more bots. And
the Chinese are going to laugh and
laugh. The Russians. Yeah. I don't I
don't know if there's anything you can
do.
I remember Elon was like looking at that
when he was trying to buy Twitter. They
were
>> Yeah, he said it was like 40% of Twitter
users were actually bots or something
like that.
>> I think it was
>> I think it was like 60% it was a high
percentage and I haven't heard him talk
about it a ton.
>> No,
>> but it's [laughter] like I'm always
clicking that on Twitter. That's the one
where cuz like that's always just been
my little private platform that no one
>> I used to get most of my news from
Twitter.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's it's interesting, but
like when you just look at the
following, I'll click someone and I'll
just be like, "Huh,
>> November 2025, you know,
>> up to 64%."
>> Yep. Deep's got it. Up to 64% of the
accounts were bots.
>> So, it's like you also have massive and
I see it on both sides of the issue. You
will see you will see
Ayal Yakobi tweet something out pro
Zionist and it's got [__] 10,000
likes in 10 minutes. You will see Ian
Carol tweet out something. Ian's been on
my show. Ian will tweet out something.
It has 10,000 likes in 10 minutes.
Neither of these make sense. Crazy. It
doesn't make any sense. It doesn't make
sense,
>> right? And that's And by the way, that's
neither of their fault, which everyone
likes to try to say like,
>> "Oh, you can prove that they're like
running." They don't know. Yeah, I don't
know these [__] accounts that touch
my
>> I don't even manage my own Twitter
account. I [laughter] I have a guy that
does it for me.
>> He called me last week. He said, "Hey,
you crossed 100,000 subscribers." I
said, "Hey, great."
>> Is that Simon?
>> Okay. Yeah, Simon. Simon doing that.
Damn it. So, it's always Simon tweeting.
I knew that already. [laughter]
That's kind of funny. It's just
>> when Simon sends his best regards. He
called me in the car. He's a good guy. I
like Simon. But like, you know, to your
point bringing up like the whole
thing. We now make these we make content
like you know the NFL playoffs or
something. Yeah. And like so and so talk
to so and so and yeah I fall in the trap
too sometimes.
>> Oh man, when I was in prison people used
to get this uh this magazine
like Hip Hop Weekly or something like I
think that's [snorts] what it was
called. And I mean, it's clearly just a
madeup tabloid, you know, with these
fake feuds and somebody was in the club
and they threw money in the face of
somebody else because of something that
happened in Atlanta.
I got kind of a kick out of it, but it
these articles sometimes led to
bloodshed. I remember two guys beating
each other to the death over who had
more money, Kanye or Jay-Z.
It's like, seriously, you guys are going
to go to solitary for that? [laughter]
There are no better reasons to go to
solitary. That's what you chose.
>> Oh my god.
>> I mean, there's not a lot to do in
prison. [laughter]
>> No,
>> I'll give them that.
>> I saw a fist fight once over whether
they should watch Love and Hip Hop
Atlanta or 110th in Park or whatever the
show was called.
>> 120th in Park. Did you have to make your
bones in a fist fight?
>> No,
>> you didn't.
>> No. No. I minded my own business. I I
made alliances with all the mafia.
>> The racial groups. The mafia was the
most important,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> Who were you? I I I always forgot. Who
Who did you have a moment of silence for
outside the house in Atlantic City after
you were in prison?
>> Oh, it was uh
>> Scarfo.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> I was like, "Come on, guys. Come
[laughter] on.
stand here all day.
>> You're like, I was in Pakistan 15 years
ago taking down al-Qaeda [laughter] and
now
>> I'm I'm actually stopping in Philly on
the way home. We're going to meet up for
dinner.
>> Oh, that's awesome. You going to Dante
and Luigi's
>> most likely.
>> Oh my god, that's funny. [laughter]
>> Can't your life, you can't make it up.
That's
>> See, I'm friends with everybody.
>> That's right.
>> Everybody. Everybody's got something
redeeming. Everybody.
>> Everyone does.
>> Not everyone.
>> Okay. I will say I'll tell you a story
and I'm going to plug my latest book as
part of the story.
>> Plug away.
>> So, I've got a book coming out called uh
Remains of the Day, a definitive guide
to Washington DC's historic cemeteries.
Go to rarebirdlit.com
rarebirdit.com
uh for the advanced autograph copies.
So, Simon and Schusters publishing it.
They liked it so much they commissioned
four more. I'm almost done with the next
one, which is Whispers in the Dirt, a
definitive guide to the Mafia Graves of
New York City.
>> Okay, so I'm about 70% done. It's going
to I'll be done. I'll be done by the end
of the year and send it to the editor.
So,
I'm in the Bronx about two months ago
just taking pictures. I'm with my
girlfriend. We're taking pictures of
different graves so I can put them in
the book. And this was supposed the
first one was supposed to be a field
guide. It was it was supposed to be
eight inches by five inches so that you
can stick it in your back pocket, but
they liked it so much they made it a
coffee table book.
So, you're going to have to like lug it
into the cemetery with you. Anyway,
back in prison, I said to one of the mob
guys, "So, you mind if I ask you, what
are you in here for?" [laughter] And he
goes like this. He goes, "They found a
body in a barrel in my storage unit. I
don't know how that body got in there.
[laughter] 100 people had access to the
storage unit." I said, "No, no, no
judgment for me. I was just curious. No
judgment." And I kind of laughed it off.
So, I'm in the Bronx
six weeks ago, whatever it is. No. And
I'm like, who is this guy again? I had I
had his name. I needed to take a picture
of the grave. His name was Bonventry,
the tall guy, right? He was like Jarro
Bonventry. Janaro the tall guy.
Bonventry. I forget his first name. So
my girlfriend said, "Who is this guy
again?" And I said, "You know, I can't
remember. He was a driver, but I don't
remember the story." So I pull up my
manuscript and I said, "Uh, the tall guy
Bonventry was a driver for this guy.
Hey, he took the boss out for whatever.
Um, the boss was killed. Bonventry was
initially assumed to have been the
hitman because they couldn't find him.
They found his body 6 months later in a
barrel in a storage unit in New Jersey.
And I said, "Oh my god." It was the
first time I put it together. It's the
body from the barrel. But he didn't tell
me the full story. The full story is the
tall guy was too tall to fit in the
barrel. [laughter]
Look at the hack. a little bit.
>> So he saw him in half.
>> He saw him in half.
>> That's what we do in Jersey, John. We
saw in half
>> and the barrel was full of glue. And it
took the corner something like 4 months
to get the glue off to do the autopsy,
which he's already saw in half. So how
much more of an autopsy do you need?
>> But then they they [snorts] sort of
pieced him together to put him in his
coffin. And I was like, "Oh, dang. He
was telling me the truth."
>> Ah.
Where is this? Is this guy still in
prison?
>> No, he's out. No,
>> which is why I didn't use his name.
>> Right.
>> Where where in Jersey?
>> Do you remember?
>> Yeah. Uh yeah, the it was in Newark, but
but he was not a New Jersey Italian. He
was a New York Italian.
>> Got it. So they brought him over here to
>> Exactly.
>> I have a chapter at the end of the book.
I go cemetery by cemetery by cemetery
and there are some like, you know, St.
Stevens or Holy Cross or whatever that
are just like overflowing with mob guys
going back to, you know, Joe the Boss
Maseria or the Clutch Hand or Lucky
Luciano who's got a magnificent private
mausoleum.
>> Um, but I have a chapter at the end of
the book on nontraditional burial
grounds like the Gowanas Canal.
>> Oh.
>> Where they're pulling bodies out of all
the time. Or there's this there's in the
Bronx there's this vacant lot that they
called the mafia graveyard.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> I got one in the Meadowlands here.
>> The Meadowlands is a great example.
>> So I've got like four, five, six of
those that I'm going to I'm going to add
at the end.
>> Okay. I'm in for that book right up my
alley.
>> I think it's going to be a good seller
already. For the one in Washington, I
just love cemeteries. And I've talked to
you about this before. Uh, I think I I
if the if it's sunny out, I'll just go
hang out in a cemetery for hours.
>> You love cemeteries. You love Abraham
Lincoln [__] Yeah.
>> What else is on the list?
>> I lost the [__] though.
>> You did lose the [__]
>> Yeah. Thank God. It was way too
expensive. Anyway, my I'm going to go
visit my son uh tomorrow and um he said
he loves the Lincoln stuff as much as I
do. He said, "Dad, there's this enormous
um antique mall in Indianapolis, and I
think they have Lincoln stuff there, so
we're going Indianapolis on Saturday.
[laughter]
>> Have fun." But anyway, um
I was shocked when I went to Amazon and
found that nobody had ever written a
book on the cemeteries of Washington,
DC.
There are like a dozen books on
Arlington Cemetery, but I thought, well,
I'll write one.
>> That's cool.
>> Yeah.
>> Right up your alley.
>> And it's I I did purposely I did the
biographies
not of the most famous people in the
cemeteries. Everybody knows about the
famous people in the cemeteries. I chose
the most interesting people in the
cemeteries.
>> Now, how do you define interesting?
>> If John says they're interesting, they
go in the book. [laughter]
So, would you how would you go about
your research with this? Did you go to
the cemetery and like go read a name and
say, "Well, let me Google this guy." And
then eventually come up with something.
>> That was part of it. I'm a big fan of
the um website uh findrave.com,
>> which is immensely helpful. But what I
did is if somebody looked like they
might or could be interesting, I would
just go to the Library of Congress and
look up their original uh obituary.
Meaning when you say look like they
might be interesting, not just you're
standing at their grave site and you're
like, I like the way they wrote the
name.
>> No, like I Google a guy that I've never
heard of and it says he was a
Revolutionary War veteran. It's like
that could be interesting. I'll check it
out. I write it write myself a little
note. There's a guy just as one random
example.
>> I'll give you two random examples. But
one this little overgrown gravestone at
Congressional Cemetery, the guy's all by
himself. There's no wife. There's no
kid. It's just him. the the stone is
old. He died in 1838. Born in 1778, died
in 1838.
And he's among like a bunch of, you
know, vice presidents and speakers of
the house. I'm like, who is this guy? I
never heard of this guy. I don't even
remember his name now. He's in the book.
I have to look it up. So, I went to the
Library of Congress and I and I looked
him up and oh my god, what a story.
[laughter]
This guy was a midlevel nobody at the
Department of the Treasury, right? He
would just sit at his desk with his big
ledgers and he would just write numbers.
And then in 1812, the British invade
Washington. They set the capital on
fire. They set the White House on fire.
It's chaos. The president runs to Mlan,
Virginia on a horse. The first lady gets
on a horse and she runs to Leburg,
Virginia just to save themselves. The
whole city's in flames. And this guy had
the presence of mind to say, "I wonder
if anybody's thought to rescue the
Declaration of Independence."
>> Nicholas Cage before Nicholas Cage.
>> He gets on a horse while the British are
shooting everybody, you know, gets in
his horse, rides over to the building
that housed the National Archives.
There's the Declaration of Independence,
the Constitution, the Bill of Rights,
and George Washington's military
commission. and he rolls them up into a
sheet, tucks them under his arm, and he
rides out to Lowden County, Virginia,
and puts them in the rafters of a
friend's barn for three years.
>> For they were there for three years.
>> For three years. And then when the
British are finally pushed out, he goes
and gets him and he brings him back and
oh my god, he's big national hero.
>> Except
>> what's his name again?
>> I have to look it up. God damn it, John.
>> I know. I kicked myself. I can find it
while we're talking. So the problem was
that as a person [clears throat] he was
just a dick
>> and everybody hated him. All of his
co-workers hated him. He he had no
personality. He was just not
>> Steven Pleasanton.
>> Steven Pleasanton. That is him right
there. Thank you.
>> He looks like a dick. I'm not going to
lie. Look at that picture. So, a group
of a group of people went to the
Secretary of the Treasury and they said,
"Look, we know he's a national hero and
all, [laughter] but we just can't work
with this guy, and if you don't fire
him, we're going to we're going to
resign."
>> Oh, he got fired.
>> So, they didn't want to fire him, fire
him. So, they made him the director of
the US Commission on Lighouses.
And so
he ended up not only helping to invent
the franal lens which we use today which
is like makes it 10 times brighter as
the l because back then they were using
candles right you can't see a freaking
candle from a mile away in a ship but
with this fraal lens that he helped to
develop and for the first time since the
founding of the country he actually
balanced the budget of the US convention
of lighouses see saving the declaration
of independence He sounds a little
oddest.
>> He's a dick,
>> right?
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> Like what a dick.
>> There's There's
>> Shout out Steven Pleasanton.
>> Yeah, good Steven. Good for Steven
Pleasanton. 1776. I I found 1778 that he
was born. Oh, 1855. Yeah.
>> Disagreeing with CIA.
>> Yeah, I'm doing my Hey, and I just read
my bio from Simon and Schustster the
other day. Yesterday for the first time
and it said uh
>> journalist and historian John Kuryako.
And I was like, "Oh, okay.
>> That's great.
>> I'll take that." So, get this. I'm at uh
>> I'm at Rock Creek Cemetery, which is the
biggest and the nicest cemetery in
Washington. [clears throat]
>> 60 70 80,000 graves there. It's a goodiz
cemetery. And um all the rich people are
buried in the front like you know the
the Woodwards and the Lothrops and the
Blooming Dales and the you know,
Goldfinles, whatever their name was. Uh
whatever whatever the name was. All the
people that that were rich in the 19th
century that nobody can remember why
they're important. So, I go to the very
back of the ceme I go to the very back
of the cemetery and um there's a traffic
island there that has this magnificent
private family mausoleum. So, I just
wrote myself a note. It was the Butler
family. And um
and I went to look in the in the door of
the mausoleum and the the tomb was glass
inside. So you can see these very
expensive bronze coffins
>> that had the two Butler brothers, their
wives, a daughter, and a grandson who
was like six when he died. So I wrote
myself this note, went to the Library of
Congress. Turns out these guys were
fascinating.
They wanted to be chemists. They wanted
to go to college and be chemists. They
were born right after the Civil War
ended. Butler was their name. And
when they got to be, you know, high
school age, almost high school age,
their dad was like, "Yeah, you're not
going to be chemists. You're going to be
bakers."
>> Bakers.
>> Bakers. Yeah. We don't have money to
send you to college to be fancy
chemists. you're going to be bakers. And
he arranged for them an a uh an
apprenticeship at a local bakery. They
hated it. So when the baker finally
retired, he turned over the business to
them. They just hated [snorts]
they hated every act of being a baker.
So they said to each other, "What if we
invent this machine
that will mix all this [__] for us so we
don't have to do it?"
>> Oh [__] So you power it with your feet
like the old time sewing machines.
>> So they invented the first mixer and
they patented it and they were able to
sell it all the way out to the frontier
which at the time was Cincinnati.
So they start making some making some
money thanks to this new fangled mixing
machine, right? And then they said,
"What if we invent another machine that
cuts the dough so that every loaf is
exactly the same size, shape, and
weight?" And they made a conveyor belt
with a an arm that came down and cut the
dough. Revolutionized baking nationwide.
They were able to sell that all the way
out to like, you know, St. Louis and
then later on to uh to Denver.
And then they said,"What if we instead
of using water to make the bread, what
if we use milk? What would that taste
like?" It made it very fluffy and light.
Then they came up with this idea.
Newspapers were becoming popular. And
there were young boys that would
actually deliver your newspaper to your
house called a paper boy, right? And
they said, "What if we hire boys to
deliver bread to the houses? if you make
an order by three o'clock, we'll deliver
the bread so you can have it on your
dinner table while it's still warm.
>> And then they started making cakes and
making pies and this and that.
>> By the turn of the 20th century, they
owned the entire city block behind what
is today Union Station, train station,
and they were millionaires many times
over.
Israel Butler, the older of the two
brothers, decided to retire like right
around the start of the First World War.
His brother stayed on for another couple
of years,
but they finally sold the business to
the National Biscuit Company, Nabiscoco.
And um the only thing that they changed
the the bread itself was very very
popular, but it had this terrible name.
I forget the name. It was like Mrs.
McGillicuy's delicious bread. That's not
it, but it was something like that. So
they um they sold it to Nabiscoco and um
the only change that Nabiscoco made was
they changed the name of the bread to
Wonderbread and everything remained the
same.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. Like who ever heard of these
people?
>> Never in my life.
>> I found the NFL's first black
quarterback.
Like you wouldn't even know that there
was a black quarterback in the 50s.
>> In the 50s. Wow.
>> Mhm. He only threw like four passes, but
still, why aren't we celebrating this
guy?
>> NFL. Yeah, absolutely.
>> Yeah.
>> How often do you go to cemeteries?
>> At least weekly. If I'm overseas, I go
almost every day.
>> So, you like to The overseas cemeteries
are actually interesting because they're
always so different.
>> So, completely different. I have this
wonderful book I bought at at some
obscure flea market or used bookstore.
It's called Death Rituals of Rural
Greece.
>> So there are almost no cemeteries in
Greece because
the the country is only like 2% arable.
And so the the land that's good, they
need to grow food on it. So there's this
practice, it's been a practice for
hundreds of years that you rent a grave
for 5 years. So they don't embalm in
Greece. They'll put you in the in the
ground for 5 years and then on the fifth
anniversary of your burial, they dig
you, the women of the village dig you up
with the priest, the village priest, and
then they take your by then you're just
a skeleton. If you're not just a
skeleton by then,
that means you went to hell.
>> Oh,
>> and so they put you right back.
>> I thought you were going to say it means
you were buried alive. I was like, "Oh,
shit."
>> No, it means it means you you went to
hell. So, um, but just about everybody
is is just bone by then. So they take
the skeleton apart, they wash it with
red wine, the priest blesses it, and
they put it in a little bone box, and
then in an ouary, a bone house just on
here, I'll show you a picture. Um just
uh on on shelves
until
um until it's time to build a new
church. And then they take all the bones
out and they put them underneath the
church under the foundation because
>> can't we just cremate at that point?
>> No, cremation's forbidden. Strictly
forbidden. [clears throat] You can't
cremate because
>> you put the bones in a box, but you
can't cremate.
>> I know, right?
>> You know, these these rules that humans
invent
>> and you know what's funny is none of
these rules are actually based in
religion.
>> No, it's it's some guy one day had a
bright idea and said, "This is what
we're going to do now as a religion."
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. That's pretty much it.
>> Is that's real? Oh my god.
>> Oh, yeah. There you go.
>> De's got it up. Can we blow up one of
those pictures? Whatever one you want,
De.
>> The one Oh.
>> Oh, so they put like the skull.
>> The top top left is is more accurate.
The one with the skulls is in Italy.
That's an ashuary in Greece.
>> That's so
>> And you know, I've I've struck up a
friendship with the guy. There's this um
well the nice way of saying it these
days is he's on the spectrum but
>> he's an artist.
>> He's he's not able to care for himself
>> and so they gave him as a job just take
care of the bone house. Right. So I go
over there every time I go back to my
ancestral island. I go to the village
where my family's from and um and he
lets me go through the the boxes and see
if they're my grandparents, my
great-grandparents or whatever.
>> You opening them up?
>> No, I mean if it's somebody that I know
or I'm related to, I take a picture of
the box and then I'll open it up just
to, you know, give them a kiss on the
skull or something.
>> Oh god. All right.
>> It's my great-grandparents.
>> All right. All right.
>> So So uh
>> just cut it cut it. You see the floor?
>> You see the floor there?
at the ocuary in our village. There's a
kind of a trap door and there's an area
underneath the floor. So, he let me go
down there last time. And uh it goes
back to the 19th century down there, but
I mean, I can't go any further than
that. The Turks burned all of our
records,
>> so we don't know really anything about
where we come from.
>> And then, you know, people are buried
under churches. I did I did find one
relative. This is my great
greatgrandfather's brother um that I
found in an oushuary in
roads on the southern tip of the island.
Come on. Where is he? He was a priest
and so they kept him. They didn't they
didn't bury him under the uh there he
is. Oh,
>> the perks of being a priest in this
life, huh?
>> Yeah. Um and then the next picture is a
picture of him. [sighs and gasps]
So, you can he get lucky sometimes.
Oh yeah. Yeah. High priest kind of guy.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He was a he was a big deal.
Yeah. I said to
>> looks like you.
>> Yeah. I said to my cousin who who also
has an interest in our family genealogy.
Um I said, "Yeah, you know, my
grandmother told me he was uh eaten by a
shark. He was diving for sponges and he
was eaten by a shark."
>> No.
>> My cousin said that's not true.
>> I said, "Oh, that's always the story we
heard." He said the Turks executed him
because he was teaching children how to
speak Greek during the Ottoman
occupation and they threw his body in
the sea and the sharks ate him.
But he said the Turks murdered him,
>> which gives me just another reason to
hate Turks.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> The Ottoman Empire is one that's
overlooked.
>> And people are like, "Oh, no. It was
okay in the Ottomans because if you just
paid your taxes, you could freely
practice Christianity. [__]
>> Yeah.
>> What country are you from where they
were so kind to you that if you paid
your taxes, you could do your thing.
[snorts] What a joke.
[laughter]
>> You're funny. You're just funny like how
you you get so upset and then you go
back to laughing right afterwards. It's
great.
Well, I don't know how we got on that
tangent about skulls and cemeteries.
>> It was my book. My book.
>> It was very, very interesting.
>> The tall guy.
>> But, you know, back to the to the world
of the living, at least for now.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, in in some of our earlier
conversations, we were talking about the
different countries of nuclear weapons
and obviously the the bombing that
happened of Iran's facilities
>> in June and everything, but what you
know,
>> may I add one other thing about that,
>> please? Yeah.
So, this is something that most
Americans don't understand or haven't
thought about and which most Israelis
just deny because it doesn't fit into
their worldview. But these Israeli
attacks on Iran have now forced the
Iranians to develop a nuclear weapon.
>> Um, they had no u uranium that was that
was weapons ready or weapons capable.
And besides that, they don't have a
delivery system. I would bet my next
paycheck that that's what they're going
to start developing now. Because if all
they have to look forward to is
continued Israeli bombing and
assassination and infiltration,
you know, the threat is existential for
them, too. And so they're going to have
to do something to defend themselves.
And the only thing that they can do at
this point is to develop a nuclear
deterrent.
>> No. Why did you say earlier, cuz we got
off this, that in hindsight then
you think that that when the US ended up
bombing this was okay?
>> Because I think that the Israelis really
would have used a nuclear weapon.
>> That's the
>> that's that's where the word existential
comes from.
>> Meaning, you don't think that was just
like a threat and [clears throat]
position?
>> I think that they really intended to do
it.
>> Okay. So,
this is something I've been thinking
about a lot more recently, and I hate
that I have to think about it, but I
used to have this picture in my first
studio at my parents house. There were
two pictures on one of the walls. The
top picture was of the nuclear bomb test
at Bikini Toll. Oh, yeah. In
>> a famous one,
>> 47. Yeah, something like that.
>> Something like that.
>> And the one below it was the picture of
Adam and the hand of God, but instead of
the hand of God, it was a robot. And the
idea is it was like a juosition in my
head of like
>> the ability we invented to wipe
ourselves out as a species at the time
you know 80 years ago whatever
>> versus the ability that's coming now
where you know with AI and we don't know
what it could be if that is another
threat we build for ourselves that that
that could wipe us out. And part of it
was I was looking at AI as like maybe we
can be hopeful here because for all the
problems in the world, people have been
prudent enough even in the worst of
situations for 75 80 years to not hit
that red button with a nuke and we all
have this mutual destruction kind of
thing going on because so many countries
have them. I will admit that over the
past couple years, I've thought more and
more and more about just how tenuous
that might be and how realistic
I hate even saying this, but how
realistic it could be that at some point
somewhere in the notsodistant future
somebody uses a nuclear bomb. So, two
questions. One,
>> how realistic is that? And two,
if that does happen, and I guess it
would depend on where as well, what is
the aftermath of that look like,
>> right?
I think it's something that we do have
to fear. I could see the Israelis using
one on Iran. I could see the Indians and
Pakistanis using them against each
other. Um,
what does the aftermath look like? I I
suppose it depends. You know, we talk
about tactical nuclear weapons,
battlefield, battlefield nuclear weapons
that supposedly, you know, aren't going
to have the catastrophic fallout that
Hiroshima and Nagasaki had or that a
modern full-sized nuclear weapon would
have, but I'm not sure that it really
matters. Um,
you know, if if we were having this
conversation right after the Second
World War, I'd say, "Wow, the world has
learned its lesson. It's going to be
mutually assured destruction. This is
going to be a policy that's adopted by
every country. Then we negotiated the
nuclear non-prololiferation treaty."
Those days are gone. You know, you got
the North Koreans, the Indians, the
Pakistanis, now maybe the Iranians, the
Israelis.
Do you trust any of those countries? Not
really.
None of them. So, I'm not sure what the
aftermath would be. I suppose
I suppose if the Indians and the
Pakistanis went at it, they'd lob one on
each other and that would be the end of
it, right?
>> What do you think the world would do in
the aftermath of that?
>> What could the world do? We're going to
run to the United Nations and issue a
very strongly worded statement. And
that's really what it comes down to.
That's it.
>> And what are you going to do? Overthrow
a government? Attack a government
because it's used a nuclear a nuclear
weapon. What if it has more nuclear
weapons? And then they use it against
you or against your troops as they're
landing or
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I don't know.
>> I guess size of country obviously
matters a lot too. So like if North
Korea used one, all due respect,
>> you know, which is a concern.
>> Mhm.
>> I mean, they're gone.
>> I would I would think so. Yeah. And that
like that's the one
saving grace I think of in my head. I'm
like if someone tried to do it to us,
>> we'd have to respond.
>> You're done. Like like if they did one
here, which would be catastrophic to be
very clear.
>> They're gone.
>> Yeah. I can't help but to think that if
if we were to be attacked with nuclear
weapons, we would have to respond using
nuclear weapons. Terrible, terrible
thing. But you have to respond.
And I agree with you. If it were to be
the North Koreans, tomorrow North Korea
wouldn't exist,
>> right? Which is a, you know,
>> Yeah.
>> It's impossible to fathom something like
that. And, you know,
>> World War II, people relitigate that all
the time. And I understand that.
>> Sure.
>> I do. Certainly.
>> I mean, that's that's a that's a crazy
thing that had to happen.
It hasn't happened since, you know, and
and that's why like when
you know, you have Israel threatening to
use nuclear weapons, like, you know,
they're a powerful country, but they're
the size of New Jersey.
>> Mhm.
>> Like, how I I don't understand
why they'd be so careless as to do that
because it doesn't take much for them to
be gone.
>> No.
>> You know, like what what is the what is
the thought process there? And like now
you even have insult to injury. You got
like Jonathan Pard running for Knesset.
>> Yeah. How do you like that?
>> On a on a platform of we should be able
to use nukes. Like are you [__]
>> Which was another issue that every
single Israeli prime minister lobbyed
for with every president. You got to
release Pard. You got to release Pard.
No, he's doing every day of the 30
years. And he did every single day.
>> But then we let him go back or not back.
We let him go there.
>> And they gave him a parade and a hero's
welcome and an Israeli passport and now
he's running for the Knesset.
>> Does that just like piss you off to no
end?
>> Yeah, very much so.
I was having lunch with a guy, nice guy
a few weeks ago who was like asking me
about different things on this issue.
[laughter]
And at one point he said he said, "Well,
doesn't MSAD have a
have a policy that they don't spy on
Americans?" And we were in Cypriani and
I, you know, that's a very tightly
packed place.
>> And I just like I was very hung over,
but I literally like fell off my chair
laughing. Other people were looking at
me and I'm like, "Yeah, no. They totally
have that policy." And he's like, he's
like, "Yeah, no. They they don't do."
I'm like, "Are you [__] kidding me?
They're like the number one threat of
spying." He's like, "Name one." And I'm
like, "John." And he's he wasn't even
MSAD. He was military intelligence. It
was like below MSAD.
>> Yes. Very much below MSD.
>> What the [__] You know, and he was
handled by what's his name? The dude who
did the Ikeman drop.
>> Oh my god. I didn't know that.
>> And yo, yeah. Yeah. What the [__] is
that guy's name again?
>> Oh my god. Uh, Rafi Rafi
Ravi Itan. Rafi Eton.
>> Yes,
>> I think that I think is his name. That
was like his hand. That was Pard's
handler who was, you know, a longtime
>> massage guy and everything. But I'm like
>> I was like, "All right, so that was
right."
>> Oh my god.
>> I'm like, "Dude, you know what? One of
the most compelling
things you'll ever see is [laughter]
when when you and Boo Damonte were on
Danny Jones together and
you were talking about that you two are
from different eras at CIA and you both
had the same experience of one of the
first days once you're in there and have
your job, whatever it may be, they take
you to a room. You're not allowed to say
what it's called, but call it the red
room. They're like, "Here are the number
one espionage threats." And it's like
Israel, China, and Russia. Mhm.
>> That's wild. You know,
>> it's wild. And you can add Cuba and
France.
>> I've heard I've heard France goes crazy.
>> You know, the French, we had
we had a little kurfuffle in the early
90s with the French.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> And they were very angry with us
>> about what?
>> Deservedly so. One of our young junior
first tour guys got caught just going
pushing a little too far. So they
expelled him and they expelled the chief
and they expelled a whole bunch of
people. And so for three, four years we
had a tough time. But the French were
just such dicks about it that we ended
up um getting orders that we weren't
even allowed to transit de Gaul airport.
And that was the only reason I was ever
in France was just to catch a connecting
flight at De Gaul to go here, there,
wherever in the Middle East. Uh but a
buddy of mine was I I forget where he
was going. somewhere in the Middle East
and he he went no it was in Africa. He
was going to Africa and the only way to
get to Africa was through Paris at the
time. Now you can just go directly to uh
Morocco and then onward from there. But
they took his laptop. He had a he had a
secure laptop. So they're like turn it
on. So he turns it on. Open it up. He's
like I'm not going to open it up. I have
a diplomatic passport. I'm on the
diplomatic business of the United
States. this is the the possess the uh
the property rather of the US Department
of State. I'm not opening it up. So they
took it in a back room. He said they had
a railroad spike fastened to a table and
they just slammed it down on the
railroad spike went all the way through
the laptop and then they pulled it off
and gave him his laptop back. So
headquarters was like, "Okay, nobody can
transit air uh de Gaul airport anymore."
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. They're just jerks about it.
>> I've heard that they are incredibly
[clears throat] talented in
>> They're very talented. When I was
overseas in uh Pakistan, my boss asked
me if I would uh meet with a French
intelligence officer. I said, "Sure." I
was meeting with foreign intelligence
officers almost every day and you just
trade, you know, hey, I heard there's a
safe house over here. I heard, "Hey, we
they give me al-Qaeda safe house over
there." And we just trade some
information. So, uh,
this French guy calls me and he says,
"Meet me at the corner of, you know, A
and B." I'm like, "Okay, you don't just
want to meet at a restaurant or
something?" "No, no, meet me at this
corner." So, I go to this corner. It's
in a residential neighborhood. I'm like,
"What? Does he live here? Like, why
would he want me to come here?" And I'm
standing on the corner and he comes
peeling down the street, makes a quick
right, reaches over and opens my door,
and he's like, "Get in."
And I said, "Oh, no, no, no, no, no."
>> [laughter]
>> I said, "I don't work for you and you're
not using tradecraft on me." I said, "I
parked right over here. I'll meet you at
the Pearl Hotel restaurant coffee bar.
Not going to [__] let you do a
there's a term of art for the for the
kind that kind of a pickup." No, no, no,
no. You're not recruiting me.
>> Yeah. We're going to have a cup of
coffee and that's it. And then I never
saw him again after the coffee.
>> So, they're tough.
>> Yeah.
And they're murderous, too. You know,
they're murderous.
>> Oh, yeah. If you're a member of, for
example, of Greenpeace, they're going to
blow your brains out if you try to, you
know, take over a ship or throw paint on
a ship or whatever. They kill a lot of
Greenpeace activists.
>> The French intelligence stuff does.
>> Yeah.
>> Like not the paramilitary.
>> No, no, no, no, no. They're happy to go
out and kill people. And that's why
that's one of the reasons why we're not
we don't have more of a presence in the
Sahel right now in Africa
>> because it's all French. They were all
French colonies and the French are there
just killing all kinds of al-Qaeda
people. Yeah, sure.
>> Oh, so they're killing al-Qaeda people.
>> Yeah, that's fine. I have no problem.
>> Right.
>> Mhm.
>> So they're like the French headqu's
nice. I mentioned in a podcast the other
day that um [clears throat] I was giving
a series of speeches all around the UK
at the beginning of the year and um
I had five speeches with
my conversant being a a
professor of English literature. I had
five speeches with a uh kind of a belist
actor and then five speeches with a
retired MI6 officer. And um one of the
things he said
unprompted by me was um you know we we
really loved working with you guys until
9/11.
And they said you all became serial
killers after 9/11. And I said, "Yeah,
unfortunately that's true. A lot of guys
just went out to just kill as many
al-Qaeda people as they could find.
Nobody was charged with a crime or I
mean none of the al-Qaeda people were
ever charged with a crime. They were
just taken care of. And then he says,
"Yeah, you and the French, my god, the
French love killing people." And I said,
"That was that was kind of my
understanding as well.
[snorts]
>> It can it it obviously is a slippery
slope because then you start cuz
remember you're the good guy,
>> right?
>> And you're thinking, I'm the good guy,
God and country. I'm going to protect my
country from the terrible Muslim
terrorists. And you go blowing brains
out and here you end up killing women
and children and taking out the whole
village. And
>> that's the problem. Like I like
>> as a taxpaying citizen that pays into
these organizations, I
>> will admit I wouldn't have a problem
with,
>> you know, very tactical strike killings
of very well
>> clear and present danger.
>> Yes,
>> is the criterion. But when you're
blowing up a [__] wedding cuz maybe
two people are there, that's where I go.
>> Or because there's a tall guy wearing
white and then you blow up the funeral.
>> Yeah.
>> The next day just to make sure you got
everybody.
>> See, that's that's what I'm saying. It
human nature
>> every time. Doesn't matter who you are.
Leads to strange slippery slopes.
>> You hindsight 2020 at every time.
>> That's right.
>> And people die. And then you create
propaganda. Then you become the bad guy.
And then there's situations where
>> there it is.
>> Yeah.
>> Right there.
>> You now you were in
trying to remember your exact timeline
because you were working at Langley. You
were the the chief historian for Saddam
Hussein leading into leading into my
first my first assignment. Yeah. In the
director of intelligence.
>> And then you were still there for a few
years. And then what year again did you
hit the farm?
Oh, I didn't go to the farm until 1997.
>> Okay, that's what I was going to say.
>> I was halfway through my career.
>> And they did they send you to Greece
first?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. When did you get to Greece in 97
as well?
>> 98.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. All right. So, that kind of takes
away the cuz what I'm what I'm
interested in is like the French
intelligence
is You're not the first guy to say that.
Like so many people are like, "Yo, look
out for them. They're [__] good." But
like first question, how well do they
get along with MI6? There's always been
a strange rivalry between France and
England. How well did those intelligence
>> It extends it extends to the uh to the
organizations themselves. Um
everybody knows by now what the five
eyes countries are. US, UK, Canada,
Australia, New Zealand.
>> We have given each other literally cart
blanch to do anything, to see anything,
to go anywhere. We don't spy on each
other. We literally had people sitting
next to us from other intelligence
services, foreign intelligence services
from those countries. So, that's a very
special relationship and it's even more
important at some place like NSA than it
is at CIA or FBI. Um, but there are no
other countries like that. You know, the
French France is a NATO country. It's in
the European Union. There's close
cooperation. We're good friends, but we
don't give them everything like we do
with the Five Eyes.
>> So, you weren't on the ground in Europe
till 98.
>> Correct.
>> But when you look at an event like
Princess Diana's death in on August
31st, 1997. It happened in Paris. It
happened in France.
>> Is there any way the French intelligence
doesn't know what happened there? I'm
not saying they did it. I'm just saying
like, do they they got to know? I would
say they probably do.
>> Yeah.
>> What do you think happened there?
>> You know, I really I really believe it
was a series of of fuckups.
>> The driver was drunk, being chased by
the paparazzi. The paparazzi were overly
aggressive.
One thing led to the other. I don't
remember if she was wearing a seat belt
or not. She had a crushed chest. I think
she wasn't.
>> Um,
yeah. I think it was just a one mistake
after another. It's possible,
>> but I don't think the royal family
assassinated her.
>> I agree.
>> Yeah. I just I never saw [snorts] the
>> I I never saw that either. And also like
I I don't I don't think Prince now King
Charles is that good of an actor. Like I
mean, you know, that was very
>> No way.
>> When you look at that,
>> obviously they had their differences for
sure, but as a mother of his kids and
everything and there was definitely
>> Mhm. some human [__] going on there.
>> I think so, too.
>> Believe it or not, I know it's very easy
to like dehumanize the royal family just
because, you know, [__] royal family,
but
>> they are humans. So,
>> yeah, they are.
>> But what's the, you know, we're talking
about nuclear war. If you mentioned the
Indian Pakistan example where maybe that
would just be isolated which you know be
for the best for everyone else but if
there was something where it wasn't
something like that and the US got
involved what is the protocol in a
situation like that? We all see the guy
with the football carrying around the
nuclear codes with with the president.
Obviously the president has the say he
makes the decision and then it's done.
But is this something that that happens
in 60 seconds if it needs to? Yeah, it
is. It's this is a much easier uh
question to answer if [snorts] if you're
asking about a situation in which the
United States is not directly involved.
>> So, yeah, we've got underground
facilities like there's one um called
Mount Weather that is uh that's on the
Virginia West Virginia line. There's
another one in Colorado where the
president, the vice president, their
families, the cabinet, congressional
leadership, their families can be
whisked away. Uh, everybody else, it's
every man for himself
>> for the rest of us. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I live three miles from the White
House, so I I don't think I'm going to
make it out. What are you going to do?
>> You won't feel anything.
>> No. No. It'll be fast. um if there's a
threat to the United States like we
believed there could be on 9/11.
>> Yeah. They'll implement that plan where
the nuclear football goes with the
president just in case we have to launch
something. The codes are in there and uh
and he can launch from Mount Weather or
from Colorado wherever he happens to be.
Air Force One just flying in circles
someplace.
The thing that I wonder in the event of
like mass nuclear strikes around the
world happening is if the story of
society completely breaks down and none
of this stuff happens. Meaning
>> right
>> it starts and there's such chaos that
people are like there is no president
including the people around him I'm like
[__] you. Who are you?
>> You have to expect that that would be a
real possibility.
>> Yeah I I would think so. I mean, look,
we've all we've all seen these
post-apocalyptic
movies or read the books. What was the
uh the Irish uh the the long road? The
something road. The road. That's what it
was called. The road. Yeah. There's been
a nuclear conflict. It's every man for
himself. And it's just a story of this
man and his son just walking down this
road. You don't know where it goes,
where they came from. Is that what it is
the roadmak.
>> Cormarmac McCarthy. That's right. Um,
they stumble on an underground bunker
and they find a bunch of canned soup
>> and then the dad dies and then the kid
just keeps walking. That's how the book
ends.
>> Huh.
>> Yeah.
>> Very Irish.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's like the good guy
always loses and the moral of the story
is there's no hope for anybody.
[laughter]
>> We got a pub right down the street if
you want.
>> There you go.
>> Want to go live that out?
>> Yeah. I I I I hate that, like I said
earlier, I hate that we even have to
think about that.
>> Yeah.
>> But it [clears throat] does feel like,
you know, you look at these different
conflicts around the world, including
the ones people don't talk about, by the
way.
>> Do you ever see the episode of the
original Star Trek where No. Where Kirk
and Spock, they beam down to this planet
and this planet, the planet's leaders
are yelling because the next door
planet, they're having a war with them.
And there's this announcement that
everybody in group A has to go to the
incinerator, right? So, you go to the
incinerator and you get incinerated. And
Kirk is like, "Whoa, what's going on
here?" And they said, "Oh, we came up
with this uh treaty with the next door
planet that since we hate each other,
we're always fighting wars. There's no
sense in blowing up all the buildings."
So we have computer models that tell us
how many people would have died if we
launch you know XYZ
uh weapon and so then we just summon
that number of people to the incinerator
and then they get incinerated so at
least we don't mess up our our our
planets
and he's like no that's not a good idea
[laughter] you have to negotiate peace
and then he of course he ends up
negotiating peace
but it's like we're headed there this
This is all predicted in 1968.
>> Yeah. Art following life following art.
>> Something I think about a lot.
[laughter] It does h it's just human
nature like that imagination comes from
something that's based in reality of how
we think.
>> Yes.
>> You know.
>> Exactly. Right.
>> I was talking with someone recently. I I
think it was Mike Rland about like
seeing the Nolan Batman series recently.
I hadn't watched it in years.
>> But the things that Christopher Nolan in
a [__] superhero series, it's like
supposed to be very fake and not of this
world.
>> The the pulse that he had his finger on
>> with society. Think about the years he
filmed those movies, 04, 07, and 2011.
They came out in '05, '08, and 2012. the
themes, elites versus the everyman,
social chaos, people out for themselves,
Gotham falling, falling from the inside.
>> Tell me that you've seen Soilent Green.
>> Soilent Green. No,
>> Soilent Green is People.
>> Soilent Green is People. So, Soilent
Green
>> came out in the early 1970s. It's one of
the great
>> science fiction films of all time.
>> Um, stars Charlton H. Oh, I love
Charlton.
>> He's a cop in the megalopouloolis.
We've had such a an explosion in
population that from Boston to DC, it's
just all one giant city. It's just all
connected. So, he's a cop in what used
to be called Philadelphia.
And
eggs are 100 bucks a piece. A jar of
jelly is 150 bucks. There's one tree
left in New York City and they had to
build a fort around it so it could be
protected. It was the only tree that's
left on the east coast. And um like I
say, he's a cop and he lives with this
old man who uh was a professor.
So nobody can afford to eat. So the
government provides these little
nutritional chips. There's Soylent
Green, which is colored green, soilent
red, soilent yellow, and it's like a
$1.98 a pound. So that's what everybody
eats, what everybody lives lives on. In
the meantime, they're
are such huge riots of hungry people
that they have these big earth movers
that just go scoop people up during
demonstrations and it it throws them
into the back of a dump truck and then
they just disappear. You don't know what
happened to them. So Charlton H
um he's barely able to make a living at
least you know he's got soil and green
he can eat and the professor decides
he's 70 years old he's sick they have
these suicide centers that you can just
go
>> you lay in a bed and um they show you a
film of just nature deer running around
and butterflies and birds tweeting.
You've never seen anything like this
before. So, as they give you the lethal
injection, that's what you get to see.
And there's classical music playing, so
it's all very nice. [snorts] He runs to
the Charlton Aston runs to the suicide
center to stop his friend from
committing suicide. And he has to break
into the place. He's too late to save
him, but
he follows the trail that they've taken
the body to. And they take the body to a
processing center where they're making
Soilent green out of all these people
that are scooping up at the
demonstrations.
And he's as they're arresting him and
beating him, he shouts, "Soilent green
is people."
>> Oh my god.
>> We used to do this thing at the CIA. We
used to do this thing at the CIA just
for fun. Like every every time you have
an operational meeting, you have to
write a very detailed like blowby-blow,
minute-by-minute account of the meeting.
And CIA cables by nature are written
only in capital letters. It's like some
thing from the 50s. They just never
changed it. [snorts] So what people
would do was they would make these
random lowercase letters,
>> but they did it so it would spell out
soilent green as people in the cable. We
would always get such a kick out of it
because it was all it would always make
its way through the system. Nobody would
pay any attention until like the one guy
is reading it and he's like, "Oh, they
did it again." [laughter]
That the scary part about that is
>> I'm going to look for
>> it reminds me of it. That kind of story
>> doesn't seem far it seems farfetched for
tomorrow, but it doesn't seem
far-fetched for somewhere in the future.
Well, this um Soilent Green, it's 1973.
I said 72. It's 73.
>> Lot of '7s was unbelievable.
>> It is on Amazon Prime right now for
3.99.
>> Okay, I'm definitely watching that.
>> Don't miss it. It's one of the great one
of the greatest science fiction movies.
>> I can't believe I haven't seen that.
>> I'm surprised.
>> I've watched a lot.
>> He did another one at the same time
called The Omega Man
>> where he was the last man on Earth.
there was some kind of pandemic and a
handful of people survived but as like
monsters
>> like uh Walking Dead kind of people
>> like I am Legend almost.
>> In fact, I am Legend was the reboot of
uh the Omega Man. Yes. Yes. Exactly.
>> Yeah. Awesome.
Love Charl him once on the street in
London. [laughter]
>> Couldn't have been nicer.
Is there anyone you [laughter] don't
know or you haven't bumped into at some
point?
>> I was with my girlfriend. We were
spending junior year abroad and uh and I
took her to see a play called The Cane
Mutiny Court Marshall and it starred
Charlton H. And he was brilliant in this
play. And she says, "Let's go around to
the stage door and see if we can meet
him." I said, "No, that's it's such a
cliche. No, I don't want to bother the
man and he's not going to want to be
bothered after working for two hours on
stage like that." She's like, "Please, I
love Charlton." So we ran around back
and it was I don't know half a dozen
other people back there and he came out
and could not have been any nicer, more
cordial, just a a lovely guy.
>> [__] Moses right there.
>> I know, right? That's Moses. And that
voice like who in America doesn't know
that voice?
>> Oh yeah.
>> Yeah. Pretty cool.
>> Yeah. Again, can't believe I I have
watched a [__] ton of movies from the
70s. The '7s was an unbs and the '9s for
movies.
>> Oh, yes. My kids even got me a a coffee
table book called called The Stewartist
is Flying the Plane: Movies of the
1970s.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. That's loved it.
>> It's It's awesome stuff. Real quick,
John, I just got to use the bathroom,
>> of course.
>> So, we'll be right back.
>> All right, we're back. I haven't gotten
your thoughts on your very good friend
John Brennan now being in the crosshairs
of
>> He is that's the way to say it. He's in
the crosshairs of the Trump Justice
Department. A couple things I've noticed
about John Brennan over the last couple
of weeks. So, he was challenged at
George Mason University in Arlington,
Virginia by a Republican congressional
candidate who I had never heard of and
who didn't come close to winning
anything. But the guy legitimately
challenged him over, you know, his role
in the memo on a couple things. The the
memo on the Hunter Biden laptop or the
letter, I guess it is, and um and on the
CIA's analysis that Russia was behind
>> the Trump election.
In the video that was shared widely on
Twitter,
Brennan actually pokes the guy in the
chest several times. Besides that being
assault,
[laughter]
that was the first time in the 35 years
that I've known John Brennan that I ever
saw him lose his composure
>> ever.
>> It's getting to him.
>> It's getting to him. He went on MSNBC
that night
looking exhausted
and old beyond his ears
and he disingenuously said, "I don't
know why they're doing this to me. I
don't understand. I didn't do anything
wrong." I mean, even by MSNBC standards,
it was not believable or credible.
And then just a few days later,
somebody some reporter shouted a
question at him. It wasn't a reporter.
It was in the metro. It was a guy who
may have been a reporter now in
retrospect. Anyway, whoever it was, it
was a guy in the metro.
And Brennan like went after him, went up
to him with his with his finger and
raised voice. A buddy of mine called
who's an attorney and said, "What do you
make of, you know, the John Brennan of
the last couple of weeks?" And I said,
"He's scared." Yeah,
>> that's what this is. He's scared because
they're going to find something to
charge him with. And not only
will they charge him, they have moved
the case to the Southern District of
Florida. Now, remember, you have to
charge the case in the federal district
where the crime was allegedly committed.
But what they did, I'll give you an
example. In the case of Jeffrey
Sterling, the CIA whistleblower, um,
they said that he had leaked classified
information to James Ryzen of the New
York Times. Ryzen then wrote a book. A
CIA secretary bought the book in
Virginia, so charged him in Virginia.
Well, Jeffrey lived in St. Louis. Ryzen
worked in Bethesda, Maryland, and the
New York Times is in New York. They
charged in Virginia. So, they play these
little games all the time,
>> right?
>> Well, guess what? The game can be
flipped.
And so,
the US attorney for the Eastern District
of Virginia, whom Trump just fired
recently, said, "Oh, I I'm not seeing a
crime. I'm not seeing [clears throat] a
case. The the investigation's not going
anywhere. We're going to drop it." Okay,
you're fired and we're transferring the
case to Florida because all you have to
do is say, "Yeah, John Brennan
coordinated that Hunter Biden laptop
memo. I was in Miami when I read the
memo on the MSNBC website." So, it's
that easy.
>> It's that easy. But they never think
about it coming back and biting them in
the ass.
>> And that's that's the thing, John. Like,
I think it's well documented long before
I ever knew you. like looking at John
Brennan's career and the kinds of things
he did to say nothing of the stuff that
you've illuminated for many of us since
then there there's no doubt in my mind
that he's not a good guy and that he has
done a lot of things that could
absolutely be taken into court and have
a case made against it and the
>> anger at some of the things that he's
done of course makes me want that to
happen. Mhm.
>> What I worry about is all the cases that
I think I righteously criticized that
they were using with lawfare to make
against Trump and people around him for
years there strictly because they didn't
like him.
>> I now have to be consistent in my
criticism of the lawfare because it
feels like we have now
>> the pendulum is swinging.
>> The pendulum is swung and we are setting
dangerous precedents of political
retribution. So much so that you have
guys like Steve Bannon Yeah.
>> coming out and saying to people, if we
don't win in 2028, people in this room
are going to prison. And this is the
same guy who's trying to go on there and
talk about doing a third term for Trump,
which is like against the whole [__]
constitution.
>> Can't do it.
I want to
I want to read to you just a couple of
sentences
from
former attorney general of the United
States and associate justice of the
Supreme Court, Robert Jackson.
>> He said something that was very famous.
>> Um he was also one of the judges at the
Nuremberg trials. This is like one of
the most important judges we've ever
had,
>> ever. Um, actually, let me find it. But
he said something in um
in a dinner at a dinner event for
attorneys. His speech was called the
federal prosecutor.
And I think I found it.
He said a couple things in this speech.
He said it is not the function of
government to keep the citizen from
falling to error.
>> It is the function of the citizen to
keep the government from falling to
error.
>> This and to me this is the most
important thing he said. With the law
books filled with a great assortment of
crimes, a prosecutor stands a fair
chance of finding at least a technical
violation of some act on the part of
almost anyone.
>> Yes. In such a case, it is not a
question of discovering the commission
of a crime and then looking for the man
who has committed it. It's a question of
picking the man and then searching the
law books or putting investigators to
work to pin some offense on him.
>> Oh, that's the Stalin bar. Show me the
man, I'll show you the crime.
>> And there it is.
>> Oh my god.
>> And here we are 85 years later still
having the same debates.
>> Oh wow.
>> Yeah. Now, let me make that personal for
a minute.
You [__] hate that guy.
>> I do.
>> And righteously so. I hate him for you.
John Brennan. He ruined your life. He I
believe committed crimes, by the way, to
to ruin your life. If you look at the
emails with him and Eric Holder and just
some of the stuff he did,
>> it's a guy who runs out and says, "Yeah,
we shouldn't torture people." When he
wrote the [__] torture,
>> he was the godfather of torture
>> program. Yeah.
Is there a part of you that would just
love vengeance there?
>> Oh, yeah. I would love love to see John
Brennan go to prison. Even if it was
just for a day or a week, just to be
dragged down into the muck like he did
to me and to Jeffrey Sterling and to Ed
Snowden and so many of the rest of us.
On the other hand,
I believe in Robert Jackson and what he
said
>> and I think that's what makes America
great. Yes, that's what makes us the
greatest country in the world is we're
governed by the rule of law. If he has
legitimately committed crimes, and I
believe he has,
>> he should be prosecuted. If there are
others
who are under investigation
who are subject to prosecutors scouring
the law books looking for a crime, I I
would prefer not to see something like
that happen.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It just it feels very
scaring me a little bit
>> the the vitriol and anger and it's it's
human. I I asked a friend of mine. I
have a friend at the Justice Department
who's not working on the Brennan case,
but who, you know, has friends and
colleagues who are. And I said I said,
"Why hasn't Brennan been charged yet? I
mean, they charged Comey with some silly
crime that's probably going to get
thrown out. Why haven't they charged
Brennan?" And he said, "Um, because they
want to get that one right." M. Mhm.
Yeah.
They have an interesting
perspective on Brennan. You know, most
federal crimes have a 5-year statute of
limitations. Most
um what we've heard Brennan would be
charged with
has either a 5-year or a one-year
statute of limitations. And they're
they're talking about contempt of
Congress. big deal. The federal
sentencing guideline calls for no prison
time,
>> right?
>> So, who cares if he if he was in
contempt of Congress? I don't care. Um,
lying to Congress, he probably has
crossed the statute of limitations. They
probably can't charge him. But what
their idea is is that the Hunter Biden
laptop memo, the Russia NIE, the Russia
analysis was all part of an ongoing
conspiracy
to deny American voters
their dulyeleed
president.
So, the statute of limitations keeps
restarting itself every day so long as
this this uh conspiracy continues. And
honestly, I think they've got him on
that. I That's the thing. I think they
might, too. And this is where this is
where it gets weird for me
because no man's above the law, right?
And it should it should be.
>> We sent a vice president of the United
States to prison.
>> Yeah, that was Spiro.
>> Spiro Agno, right? They they got the
Greek guy.
>> Yeah, but he wasn't Orthodox, so it
doesn't count.
>> Okay. All right.
>> Yeah.
>> But like I look at that and I go,
>> is the slippery slope of letting a man
like John Brennan be above the law
>> worse than the slippery slope,
>> right,
>> of the precedents that we are setting
across the board right now.
>> And it's almost like, and people at home
don't want to hear this. I don't want to
hear this either, especially when it
comes to a guy like John Brennan. But
it's almost like
somebody here, we used this example for
something else earlier, but someone here
has to be the Martin Luther King and
just be like,
>> we we're bigger than this.
>> We're not doing this because it's
making, you know, we're othering each
other in this country. I I
>> see. And that's exactly why Joe Biden
should have pardoned Donald Trump.
So many people believed he that's what
he was going to do. Just like Gerald
Ford pardoned Richard Nixon for the for
the betterment of the country. Yes.
Bring the American people back together
again. Joe Biden should have pardoned
all of those Republicans.
>> I agree.
>> And he didn't.
>> I agree. I agree with you really very
much on this issue that at the end of
the day.
What's more important is the the
strength of the country and the unity of
the country.
It was a mistake
to charge Donald Trump with 34 felonies
for not filling out a freaking form for
the, you know, state business commission
or whatever the heck it was. That was
dumb. Uh, it was a mistake to charge
him. I don't even remember what the
crime was alleged in Georgia. What was
that? Oh, he called the sec Georgia
secretary of state and said, "Find
[laughter] the votes." Okay. He was
excitable that day. It was the election.
That that's that's not a crime. That's
just a guy having a bad day. [laughter]
>> Um,
Comey, I understand they hate Comey.
Comey is an idiot, frankly, for being as
smart as he is. He's really stupid at
the same time.
>> Yeah. like to take a picture of the
shells 8647. What the [__] are you
thinking, you [__]
>> Brennan, however, is different in my
mind. I believe Brennan was trying to
enact a coup. I really believe it.
I think there's evidence that, you know,
even if even if you wanted to dress it
up and call it like a shadow coup or
something like that, however you want to
say it,
>> when you look at all the things that
were disproven that were happening on
his watch.
>> Yeah.
>> One plus one plus one plus one plus one.
It's
>> seriously. And look at it this way, too.
There were a lot of bad guys at the CIA
at the time that I was there in those
circles, right? I mean, we can say
terrible things about George Tennant and
John McLaclin and Mike Morurell and Jose
Rodriguez and Rick Praau and a lot of
people. We can say a lot. There were a
lot of crimes that were committed in the
name of national security. Brennan's
different. Brennan plotted against an
elected president of the United States
and he tried to use this, you know, the
intelligence community and this lawfare
against him and we can't risk that
happening again. That that is
when you put it like that, it's it's
about as sinister as it gets.
>> Yeah. Now, now here's the thing, John. I
think about this a lot.
We've been the power in the world for a
long time.
We have always had people in different
parts of power be it government,
bureaucracy,
corporate which you know one feeds the
other.
>> There's a lot of crossover
>> elites etc. where there are some awful
people and people who do corrupt things
people who get away with it sometimes
because the issue becomes bigger than
the person and they're connected enough
so we slight we swipe it under sweep it
under the rug. But I get this strange
feeling
that there is this deliberate
movement now
to paint everything that America has
ever done
>> as evil. It's all bad. Every single
[__]
>> I hear that a lot. So, I say this to a
guy who was legitimately [__] over
[snorts] by the United States government
and the worst types of people in it, who
knows where evil happens and knows that
we're not perfect and knows we've done
evil [__] around the world for sure. You
know, do you have a problem with with
that narrative? Oh my god, yes. You
know, I I I go to bed at night watching
Tik Tok videos. I'll watch a hundred of
them before I finally fall asleep. And
you know, they lead me to mostly First
Amendment auditors who I just [laughter]
love. I I just love them. Uh and and um
conservative um YouTubers who will go
out on the street and say, you know,
what's the best country in the world?
And you know, do you believe the United
States is the best country in the world?
And they say, oh, you know, I would like
to live in Denmark or
this is the best country on earth.
Period. I've been to 72 countries. I'm
going to add another five more by the
end of next year. This is the best
country on earth. Of course, we have
problems because we're human. But but
the founding fathers gave us a system
that is
perfect for
resolving those problems. Right? The
three co-equal branches of government.
It's a little a skew right now, but it's
going to return to where uh where it
should be. It always does.
>> You think so?
>> I do. It always has through history. Um
and it it will again,
>> but um
>> what has to happen for it to return
there?
>> Congress needs to find where what
happened to its ball sack?
>> It vanished
>> once upon a time.
>> I remember Jimmy Carter complaining. I
was a kid. I was in high school. Jimmy
Carter complaining that uh he couldn't
get anything done because Congress
wouldn't do what he what he told him to
do and the Democrats controlled both
houses of Congress and they were like,
"We don't work for you."
>> Co-equal branches of government. Well,
we've forgotten that, right?
>> And so the Democrats are in lock step
with Joe Biden. The Republicans are in
lock step with Donald Trump. That's not
the way it's supposed to be. Yes, work
together. But look look at the 80s under
the Reagan uh presidency. Uh the
Democrats controlled the House, the
Republicans controlled the Senate for
the first four years or six years of the
either four or six, I can't remember
anymore, of the Reagan presidency, but
the speaker of the house was a
Massachusetts liberal named Tip O'Neal.
>> And what happened? The president would
invite him over for breakfast, right?
And they would sit and hash things out
because they were both gentlemen.
>> And that's how you got business done in
Washington.
>> Let's make a deal.
>> Exactly. Everything is open to
negotiation. Everything.
So, let's negotiate.
>> And you think we can get back to that?
>> I do. I think we can get back to that.
>> Mhm.
>> Besides, you know, the broad general
point, which is appreciated if Congress
has to find their balls again.
>> Yeah. They're all bums.
>> Yeah. But so how do you flush out the
attitudes that have formed on both sides
within Congress and and Senate at this
point where they don't want to do that?
>> I think that we need to elect more
independent thinkers. Listen, I made
fun, for example, I made awful fun of
Marjorie Taylor Green when she was first
elected. You know, the Jewish space
lasers and cheating on her husband. And
>> I find myself agreeing with Marjorie
Taylor Green like 80% of the time now.
>> Wow.
>> It's nuts. I haven't changed. I see
Marjorie Taylor Green as having matured
in her role as a member of Congress.
>> Yeah. Like, wait a minute. Wait a
minute. This isn't how Congress is
supposed to work.
>> What do you like about what she says?
Um, I see her as something of a of a
very out there civil libertarian
>> in the in the mold of uh
of um
Tom Massie, Thomas Massie, let's say.
She's not as smart as Thomas Massie, of
course, but they take a lot of similar
positions like uh Rand Paul is another
example. Bernie Sanders on
[clears throat] the on the Democratic
side is another one, but I think we need
more people like that. There's a guy
who's been running in the Democratic
primary against Nancy Pelosi for years.
I met him in like 2016. I don't remember
his name. It's an Indian name and I I
just don't recall what it is. The guy's
an attorney. He's very smart, very
bright guy. He's an activist.
We need for him to run against people
like Nancy Pelosi. I I think my lucky
star is that Nancy Pelissi is not
running for re-election. Of course,
she's so young at 82, right?
>> That's the guy. That's the guy. I met
him at the uh San Francisco Film
Festival when we we stopped and chatted.
I had never heard of him before.
>> How do you say that name? I just
butchered that.
>> Chakraarti.
>> Chuckardi. I've got a friend um he's an
originally Indian naturalized American.
Bert Thacker. Shout out to Bert Thacker.
>> Shout out Bert.
>> Bert um
Bert's a two-time Jeopardy champion. Uh
number one. Number two, he is a former
Republican congressional candidate in
Southern California, moved to Texas, got
himself elected to the city council in
the city he went to, and is already
planning his congressional campaign.
We need to have 435 people like Bert
Thacker because then we would get stuff
done in this country. Bert cares almost
not at all about party affiliation. He
happens to be a Republican,
>> right?
>> But he just wants to get stuff solved,
>> get things done. I think a big
difference today that's causing a huge
problem which should be like the biggest
benefit ever is the fact that all of us
have a voice behind a keyboard
>> online and we police each other for
thought. Now where does that sound very
familiar from? Online that then forces
its way towards the ballot box and the
people who get elected there who are
from that same world and understand it
or if they're not from that world
understand that they have to live in it.
So, for example, your Nancy Pelosi, you
can't possibly make a deal with Donald
Trump. That won't play well on TikTok.
It won't No, you could. It won't play
well on Instagram. It won't play well on
Twitter. And you're going to be viewed
as a traitor to your people for doing
that. Whereas Nancy Pelosi could have
tied one off, you know, [__] 25 years
ago if Donald Trump were president and,
you know, come up with a deal at a
[__] K Street Steakhouse and [__]
could have actually happened, which is
exactly how Washington used to work.
Yes, you're exactly right. You knew that
if you went to the Oval Room at 9:00 on
on a Tuesday night, the entire Senate
leadership was going to be there having
stakes and trying to figure out what to
do about the budget.
>> Right. at the Trump hotel when it when
there was a Trump hotel in Washington. I
went with friends a couple of times,
more than a couple of times, and we
joked that like, my god, is there a
single member of the Republican House
leadership who's not at the bar right
now? Like literally every single one of
them, but that's how you get stuff done.
>> Yes.
When I was in college,
um it was quite common for members of
Congress to share group houses up on
Capitol Hill. You'd pack six, seven,
eight guys in a in a house because it's
expensive in Washington. You have to
maintain a house in your district,
right? And your family's probably in the
district. You still have to have
somewhere to live in Washington. So, and
they they don't really make any money.
Well, they do now.
>> Great stock pickers.
>> 220. It's like a miracle. Like a
miracle.
>> They're incredible at it. crystal ball.
So, um,
so it wasn't unusual to have, you know,
three Dems and three Republicans in a
house or four and four. They'd play
poker on Fridays, they'd go to church
together on Sundays, and then, you know,
they would argue in committee, but
they're all friends and they knew that
at the end of the day, they could
negotiate a deal.
>> And that's just not the case anymore.
>> Yeah. That's why that's where I'm having
trouble seeing how that becomes the case
again.
>> Yeah. because of how people have just
been so, you know, and I in this kind of
job, I see it all the time. You know,
how much people just jump to conclusions
on the minute they hear an opinion they
don't agree with, they're gone.
>> Yeah.
>> They're really not. But they say that.
>> Oh, I get that all the time. Listen, I'm
I'm going to say something that's going
to cause me trouble, but I'm going to
say it anyway. [sighs and gasps]
>> I gave an interview to an Indian news
outlet two weeks ago, and I didn't say
anything that I haven't said a thousand
times.
for whatever reason and this is why as a
matter of policy listen I'm serious no
more interviews to any Indian or
Pakistani news outlets ever again okay
John's policy done
>> because they just make [__] up
>> and put it in a banner headline with two
exclamation points and say that the CIA
this CIA officer finally reveals the
truth behind you know like no I told you
my information's 25 years old. Okay. So
I said one thing. I said in a
conventional conflict
India would beat Pakistan
because it has five times the people.
Yeah.
The death threats. I've lost count of
how many death threats I received. And
then the best of all like my my lawyer
is like got to keep a low profile. Just
be [laughter] aware aware of your
surroundings.
>> I know, right?
>> John's like, "Fuck you." [laughter]
>> So, I get a letter from the president of
Imran Khan's political party, right?
Whatever it's called, the Pakistan
whatever party.
>> You got a letter,
>> a letter in the mail. you and he says
that they condemn in uh in the strongest
possible terms what I said to the
Indians and they demand an immediate
apology to his excellency the former
prime minister to the members of the
party and to the people of Pakistan
>> for giving an opinion.
>> Yeah. So my lawyer is like just throw it
away just throw it away. So I didn't
throw it away. I sent him an email and I
said,
>> "Oh my god, in regards to your demand
for an apology, I wipe my ass with your
demands for an apology." [laughter]
And I hit send
and that's how I left it and I haven't
heard back from them.
So my my my lawyer is like, "Well, that
speaking offer at the uh Pakistani
military academy, yeah, you're not going
to be doing that." And I said, "No, no,
I'll never go back ever again." But they
don't they don't treat me with with
respect anyway.
>> You could have just said, "Explain Bin
Laden."
>> Yeah.
>> Exactly.
>> I mean, yeah. Like it would appear
mathematically India would
>> Yeah.
>> would body bag Pakistan. No, you know,
no Pakistan. No disrespect. It's just,
you know,
>> and you know why they hate each other so
much? Because they're exactly alike.
That's why. It used to be one country,
>> right? India, Pakistan and Bangladesh
was one country called called the Indian
subcontinent, right? And then in 1947,
India and Pakistan had a brutal bloody
war and they split off.
>> So all the Muslims went west to Pakistan
and all the Hindus went east to uh to
India. But now there are more Muslims
than there are you know pretty much
anybody else in they have a higher birth
rate in India. But anyway, and then by
1971, I think it was, Bangladesh is
like, "Screw this. They're part of
Pakistan." They were called East
Pakistan. And they're like, "Pakistan's
all the way over there. We disagree with
everything. So, we're going to be
independent, too." And they created
Bangladesh.
>> Okay. Well, India has five times more
people than Pakistan does. And the
Bangladeshies like the Indians, and the
Afghans like the Indians and hate the
Pakistanis. So if you're Pakistan and
you're outmanned and surrounded by your
enemies, you going to win that fight?
>> Yeah. They don't seem to have like a lot
of friends.
>> No.
>> Right.
>> No. Cuz they write threatening letters
and expect immediate action.
>> I love that they wanted a retraction.
>> Yeah. A retraction.
>> Last time I was in your country, I land
I ran the greatest targeting mission in
modern history. Don't [__] with me.
>> That's right.
And he wants a he he neglected to say in
the letter that his prime minister is in
prison right now.
>> Oh, he's in prison. Oh, yeah. Why is he
in prison?
>> Oh, for all kinds of reasons. Treason
and
>> he's still prime minister.
>> No, no, they deposed him.
>> So, he's not running it from the prison
cell.
>> No. Well, he's trying he's running the
party from his prison cell. Got it. They
got a new prime minister.
>> Ah, it's so awkward.
>> Yeah. And he wants an apology from me.
Now I think you should apologize to all
of the people of Pakistan for being a
you know corrupt
>> typical corrupt leader in Pakistan.
They're all corrupt. Listen, one time I
was with uh with a colleague, a more
senior colleague. We went to see Benazir
Bhau. We went to see Benazir Bhau. She
was in exile in Dubai
and [snorts] um
her husband was this guy Zardari. I
think his first name is Hussein,
something like that. And uh
so we're at the uh we're at her
beachfront mansion, her $10 million
beachfront mansion in Dubai. This is a
woman who was making, you know, 60 grand
a year as prime minister.
>> Hey, listen. Good investor,
>> right?
So we hear a car pulling up outside and
she said something off-handedly that has
just been ingrained in my mind ever
since. She says, "So [snorts] help me
God. If he's pulling up in another
Bentley, I'm going to lose my mind."
[laughter]
And my boss and I kind of look at each
other like,
"Corrupt a little bit?"
>> Yeah.
>> You make 60 grand a year. How many
Bentleys do you have with your $10
million beachfront house in Dubai? And
then she went back, became prime
minister again, got shot in the head.
Now he's the president of Pakistan. her
husband, her corrupt husband.
>> Funny how the world works.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, that is the thing. The
patterns are the same everywhere in
different different societies. Human
nature.
>> It's human nature. You get people that
get into powerful positions that have
connections to be able to do things that
the average person can't.
>> Whether it's legal or not, they do it.
>> It's you're 100% it's it is human
nature. And like now in the internet
era, we can just see it more right in
front.
>> I think you're exactly right about that.
Yeah, the the information is much more
re readily available for us. It's just
there almost instantaneously.
How much in your career at CIA did you
either see directly or get an inkling or
a vibe
of
say elite forces that were not a part of
CIA playing roles or having say or
having some sort of influence over
decisions that the agency was making.
>> I didn't.
>> Never.
>> No. It was always the other way around.
After 911, we were short on um special
forces guys. You know, we had this thing
called the special activities division
and then within the counterterrorism
center, there was the special activities
group. Um but we needed
operators like not the ones like John
that were going to, you know, whine and
dine the guy and recruit him. Exactly.
And so we just borrowed people from the
special forces. So all of a sudden, I
mean, like in in the matter of a week or
two after 911,
>> we've got SEALs, we have Delta, we have
Rangers, we have all these people,
>> and they're all
they're not what you might imagine.
They're not they're not these buff, you
know, hemen that stepped out of a
magazine. They had five days beard,
little bit of a gut. they could do some
heavy drinking and then get up and run
five miles, which I never understood.
Um, but they they knew exactly what the
mission was and by God, they were happy
to get on a plane, jump out the back of
it, and then do the mission and then
figure out how to rescue them later.
>> I've had a couple of those guys sitting
here.
>> Yeah, they're they're very, very tough
guys. Yeah,
>> they're built a little different.
>> Yeah, they are. I've never understood
how
I've never understood how guys like that
can negotiate
the
psychological weight of what comes with
their jobs. It is a the fact that you
haven't figured that out is not
reassuring because I sit here and wonder
the same thing sometimes. There is the
only thing I can come up with is there's
just a different gene. I think that's
it. I've got two friends. One was a
medic um on Seal Team 2. He's an older
guy. He's about eight years older than I
am. So, this is when the SEAL teams were
first created out of what used to be
called the underwater demolition teams.
And I've got a buddy who's currently a
SEAL. I won't say which team. He's the
son-in-law of a very close friend of
mine.
He does struggle with these issues. My
my older friend from Seal Team 2 sleeps
like a baby every night. No problem.
>> I think it's person to person.
>> I think it is
>> right.
>> Yeah.
>> But also they pick certain guys for
certain teams or certain missions.
>> That's right.
>> Who maybe they've
tested under scrutiny and stress. Not to
say, by the way, that sometimes once the
guys are done their career and come
home, they don't bring it home with
them.
>> And they frequently do.
>> Oh, yeah. They frequently do and it's
it's a sad thing to see.
>> Sad. But when when they're in there,
there's something about like reach go
>> mission
>> and that's it.
>> All about the mission.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, glad they're on my side,
though.
>> Yeah. Me, too.
>> Right.
>> Yep. Got that right.
>> So, they were just And I mean, I've
talked with guys about this before. It
was obviously like a [__] show right
after 9/11. All hands on deck. But
>> basically a lot the way you're
explaining it is a lot of these guys
minus just some of the basic like on the
ground forces we know from the
paramilitary operation that happened
right away in Afghanistan. But a lot of
these guys were literally like hey
you're in you're right in you're in
>> they just showed up one day. I'm telling
you at at the counterterrorism center
>> we we more than doubled in size within
two three days.
>> Wow. And then even after that all these
all these special forces guys just
arrived like okay where do we go and
then they started doing their thing.
>> And when how soon was it after the
towers came down that you were first
approached about with the enhanced
interrogation?
>> Oh it was quite some time. Towers came
down in September 11th. We started
bombing Afghanistan in early October.
Um, it was in late October that Mitchell
and Jessen were introduced to George
Tennant at a at a cocktail party. They
pitched the so-called enhanced
interrogation techniques. I think we
signed the contract in January.
Uh, and then we were just waiting to see
who's the first guy we're going to
catch. We caught up with a beta in
March.
>> Yeah, I was going to say we're going to
Pakistan
>> and then I was approached the first week
of May
>> of 2002.
>> Okay. And then you were still in there
for a few years afterwards. I mean,
obviously that is the core part of your
story. We've told that on episode 249
and 250 a bunch before. We don't have to
go through all that.
>> Sure.
>> But
>> that was a disturbing thing that you saw
at CIA.
>> Yeah.
Are there other things now years later
that you're willing to talk about that
you came across that maybe didn't
involve you directly like that where
people were like, "Hey, we want to
actually bring you in on this that you
just found viciously disturbing that
they were doing?"
>> No. Um I all throughout my CIA career I
I worked with people who were doing
their jobs to the highest ethical
standard. It was it was
because it post 911.
>> Mhm.
>> And everybody just kind of went nuts
because this was the greatest
intelligence failure in the CIA's
history and because it was specific to
the counterterrorism center. I think
that's why there was so much that was
sort of revealed to me. But otherwise,
no. In fact, one time
one time I was the notetaker. I was I
was living in Bahrain at the time and um
and uh Ambassador David Ransom, just an
absolutely lovely guy, one of the just
finest human beings I've ever worked
for. He was a terrific ambassador and
just a just a really great guy. Um he
would frequently ask me to be the
notetaker in his meetings with the uh
Minister of Foreign Affairs. And the
minister liked me and I liked him. his
English was better than mine, crazy as
that might sound.
>> But um
if there was something sensitive that
the ambassador needed to raise, he would
always mention it to me in the car on
the way to the foreign ministry like,
"Don't let me forget to say X." And I'd
jot down a note. So we went to see the
foreign minister one time and um
and he did forget to say X. And so at
the end of the meeting, and these
meetings would go two hours, he turned
to me and he said, "Is there anything
else? Is there anything that I'm
forgetting?" And I said, "Yes, there's
the issue with Ambassador soandso."
And he said, "Oh, that's right."
and he said uh he said to the foreign
minister, "One of my predecessors here
in Bahrain, it's come to my attention
uh is now working for the Bob Dole
campaign and we understand that he may
come out here and ask you for money. It
is illegal for a foreign national to
contribute money to an American
political campaign." So, I just wanted
to give you a heads up. H. And the
minister says, "Oh, he's already been
here. We gave him $50,000. We didn't
realize it was illegal, but he went to
see the Amir." And the Amir gave him
$50,000.
So, [snorts]
we get back in the car and the
ambassador says, "Listen, that last
part, don't put that in the cable." He
said, "That's a hornet's nest that I
don't think either one of us want to be
involved involved in." So, I didn't put
it in the cable. You break the cable out
by issue like the ambassador's meeting
with the foreign minister Middle East
peace, the ambassador's meeting with
foreign minister uh the military
agreement with the United States,
ambassadors meeting with the foreign
minister Iran and the threat from you
know whatever. He told me not to write
that.
This was like a month or two or three
before I I left to go back to
headquarters. And I thought about it and
thought about it and thought about it
and I thought, you know, for my own
selfish reasons, what happens if I go
for my next polygraph and they ask me if
I'm aware of a crime that I didn't
report?
>> Then then it's me, then I get fired. So
I just pick up the phone one day and I
call the general counsel's office. Guy a
guy answers the phone, George, and I
said, "Hi, my name's John Kuryaku. I'm
in the uh office of Near Eastern South
Asian analysis. He goes, "Wait, Kuryaku,
are you from Ferrell, Pennsylvania?" And
I go, "What?" I go, "Yeah, I was born in
Frell, Pennsylvania." He said, "Is your
dad Chris?" And I said, "Yeah, you know
my dad?" And he said, "Your dad was the
best man in my in-laws wedding."
>> Oh my god.
>> And I said, "Oh, cool." He says, "Let's
have coffee." I said, "Okay." Better
than just reporting this crime over the
phone to a stranger.
>> So with me in the cafeteria, nice guy.
We're still friendly. Not friends, but
we're friendly. So, uh, [snorts]
so I said, you know, there's something I
I'm aware of. I don't know if it's a big
deal or not. It kind of feels like it
might be a big deal, but I don't want it
to trip me up on the polygraph. So, I
told him, he's like, oh yeah, that's a
felony. [laughter]
And I said, okay, so like, so I'm done.
I don't have to write it write it down
or anything. He said, put it in an email
and send it to me. He said, I I'll send
it over to DOJ. But at the very least,
we have to report it because if word
gets back to DOJ that you knew about it
or I knew about it or your ambassador
knew about it, we're all liable to be
prosecuted.
>> So I sent him an email and uh I don't
know a year later or so since he was
Greek and we had this Greek American
kind of group at the agency. We would
have lunch together once a month after
that once George Tennant became
director. Um, I asked him what ever
happened to uh that thing. He said,
"They didn't give a [__] Nothing ever
happened."
I said, "Okay, well, we did the right
thing."
>> You did the right thing. I wonder if it
had had two zeros at the end of that,
two extra zeros if they would have given
a little more of a [__]
>> right?
>> I mean, 50K from the Amir feels like
grab grab that change off the ashtray.
>> Listen, you know what I mean?
>> The the DCM, the deputy chief of
mission,
>> another good guy. his wife uh developed
a very serious case of breast cancer
while while we were there and she had to
be medevaced back to the United States
and the DCM went to uh curtail his his
position he had to go back take care of
his wife etc etc they had a
nine-year-old daughter at the time this
box arrives from the royal diwan it's
just a box wrapped in brown paper and um
and he said to me I I got something from
the royal dwan. And I said, "Oh, that's
kind of cool. I never got anything from
the royalty diwan, the royal palace."
And he says, "Don't leave.
I'm thinking I might need a witness."
And I said, "Okay." He opens it up.
$50,000 in cash with a getwell card to
his wife. That's what lovely people they
were.
>> They are. They remain lovely people. We
can't accept $50,000. So I walked 20 ft
to the ambassador's office and knocked
on the door and I said, "Ambassador,
you're going to want to see this." So he
comes over. He's like, "Oh, for God's
sake." And he said, "I I just got it
from the Royal Dwan." And he said,
"Okay, we need to count it. We need
witnesses." So we counted it all out. It
was 50,000. And then I wrote a cable to
the Treasury Department saying, "We're
pouching back $50,000 that's from the
Amir." And it just goes into the
Treasury
with our tax dollars.
Well, I guess thank you for the donation
to our tax revenue.
>> Yeah,
>> there's something gets used, right?
>> Yeah, it gets used. Sure.
>> Do you think that
have you discovered things in the years
since being out of CIA, which has been a
long time now?
>> Been out a long time.
>> That
shocks you. And and before you answer
that, the reason I asked that is because
whether it's CIA, NSA, Sure. Wherever,
>> a brilliant tactic that all these
bureaucracies use is they
compartmentalize people to work on what
they're working on.
>> That's right. And that's what they want
you to do. They want you to be
compartmentalized so you're not
wondering what Fred's doing down the
hall.
>> That's right.
>> Cuz it's none of your damn business what
Fred's doing down the hall. So question
remains. Are there things that you've
discovered that CIA does that
>> doesn't have to be a for bad reason
either but
>> Oh yeah I've been shocked you?
>> Yeah I've been shocked. I was shocked
with the um Vault 7 revelations in 2017.
>> The Wikileaks stuff.
>> Yeah that was shocking.
>> Now what was that?
>> Vault 7 is very complicated. Among other
things, Vault 7 showed that the CIA had
develop had developed hacking capability
where they could hack into, you know,
the Russians, the Chinese, the Iranians,
the Cubans, whomever, hack the system
and then leave traces of the hack on
purpose, but with the traces written in
cerillic or Mandarin
>> so that once they were discovered by the
IT security guys in those countries,
they'd say, "Oh,
It was the Russians that did it. They
left, look, they left one little line of
code and it's all written in Russian
>> conveniently.
>> Yeah. So, that was one thing. Another
thing that Vault 7 taught us was that
the CIA um developed the capability to
take over your car remotely by hacking
into the car's computer system to drive
you off a bridge or into a tree.
>> Now, did we discover examples of where
this was used?
>> We did not. But the conventional wisdom
among the blogersphere is that, you
know, we should ask Michael Hastings
what happened to him.
>> Um.
>> Whoa.
>> Yeah. Vault 7 also told us that the CIA
is able to take over a smart TV to turn
the the speaker into a microphone so
that it broadcasts everything taking
place in the room with the TV still off.
Well, the TV's on. So, hello.
>> Pretty impressive.
>> Hello, Langley. Yeah. How are you?
>> So, what that told me, those are very
cool. And and there were a dozen more
things that were part of Vault 7. But
what it also told me is that [snorts]
the CIA is running parallel operations
with NSA. Why is the CIA developing this
stuff? This is NSA and DARPA that should
be doing it. And NSA and DARPA are doing
it,
>> but the CIA is also doing it. How do you
like what?
>> Because
>> on the one hand
they have so much money that they can't
spend it all
>> so they just make their own NSA, make
their own DARPA. I have a buddy I sat
next to him for the first three and a
half years of my career.
>> He's now the deputy director of the CIA
for innovation. Like what's that? He was
always a computer nerd.
>> Yeah. And I remember he got a he got an
award like 1991 because he came up with
a program uh to make a very crude family
tree. Like computers were new to us at
the time. When I first started, I had
this big box that had a green screen. It
was about that big called a Delta data.
And I had an IBM Select Electric 3
typewriter next to me because half of
what we did was on this uh typewriter
still. So he came up with this crude
family tree so we could do the Saudi
royal family, the Kuwaiti royal family,
Bahini royal family, just so it's, you
know, clear when you're doing your
analysis. And they were like, "Wow, you
did that on this new computer. That's
amazing. Here's $500 and an exceptional
performance award. Now he's the deputy
director of the CIA for innovation,
which tells me that he's in charge of
all this crazy [__] that we're reading
about at Wikileaks." That's what I don't
understand though, like
why even have
DARPA or NSA if it's not just a
department of like CIA or and the other
way around with CIA being a department.
You know what I mean? Like why do you
even have separation? Because the same
you may I'll give you an example.
>> You may call on
>> [__] Tim Cook at Apple to take care
of something they need. If you're DARPA,
it's like CIA can call them too. Yeah,
sure.
>> So, why aren't they all just under one
roof?
>> Often times, it's a bureaucratic pissing
match where the Secretary of Defense
will say, "Well, C CIA does its own
thing for its own reasons. We're very
specific. Our mission is, you know, to
protect the homeland and our troops and
whatever." CIA is like, "We don't really
give a [__] about the troops. We don't
have any any troops except maybe we'll
see them in the cafeteria when we're at
some base somewhere. So, we want it for
CIA reasons." And NSA is like, "Well,
wait a minute. we're NSA. This is
exactly what we're supposed to be doing,
so we're going to be doing it.
>> But again, when you have so much money
that you can't spend it all in a fiscal
year, you end up just replicating
>> uh what the other guys are doing.
>> And does Congress even actually know
what kind of money
>> that CIA has?
>> No. How does that get hidden? single
year, year after year after year after
year, Congress appropriates more money
than the Defense Department asks for.
>> I wonder why.
>> Yeah, cuz then you're you're not weak on
defense. Those pinkos otherwise, you
know. Yeah. and and there's how many
trillions of dollars missing and after
how many years of of internal audits
Price Waterhouse Cooper just gave up and
said we don't know where this money
went. It's just gone.
>> How do you
like what what kind of
I guess look through, see through, work
with, however you want to say it, did
you have with NSA
>> during your career for things you did
and what was that like?
>> I had a good relationship with NSA. I
made a point of making that long drive
out to NSA at least once a year just to
say, "Hey, how you guys doing? What are
you working on? Let's go have a coffee
in the cafeteria." And then we would
invite them to come over to the agency.
They would always come like six or eight
at a time and we'd spend the day and
take them to the gift shop and whatever.
>> She got along.
>> Oh yeah. Always got along. And then they
would they would call and say, "Listen,
we're going to publish something in
about an hour, but you need you need to
know what this is because you work on
XYZ issue." And they would give me a
heads up so I could call the seventh
floor and say, "Listen, NSA is coming
out with something big. This is what
they're going to say." Um, and that was
a valuable relationship. Um,
even operationally
I had a good relationship with NSA to
the point where in one of my overseas
tours I worked closely with an NSA
officer and he really did me a solid.
Um,
there were a couple of phone numbers I
asked him to just start intercepting and
tell me if there's anything interesting.
and just to be a nice guy. He also began
intercepting
the phone of one of my sources.
>> And so he said to me one day, "Hey, I I
have [snorts] a present for you." And he
gives me this file and it's a transcript
of everything that my source has said.
And I was like, "This is [__]
brilliant." So now I can say, "Hey, do
you ever talk to soand so
because I know it's there. I know he
does." And then if he says, "Yeah,
actually I talked to I talked to him on
Tuesday." You did? What did he say? And
then he'll just pair it back. So I know
he's telling the truth. That's called
operational vetting.
>> And so I can write to headquarters and
say I know for 100% certainty that he's
telling me the truth.
>> Wow. So there that's interesting because
you always hear about like this inter
agency rivalry and stuff and you would
think that when CIA has their own
innovation and technology design ar
>> working together. It's just weird.
>> Yeah. And then throw in throw in the
whole nonsense about Inqel and Palunteer
where
>> please do throw it in John
>> where the CIA now is in the venture
capital business for a profit.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Which is illegal.
Um they
>> not if you're writing the laws. Not not
if you're writing the laws where
the CIA in the immediate aftermath of
9/11 created something called inqell
which is a cutesy you know play on intel
with Q from the James Bond movies in the
middle. Like I hope they didn't pay
somebody to come up with [laughter]
that. But anyway, um [snorts] it's like
the kind of famous story that the
>> that the tourism board of Scotland spent
$150,000
hiring a consulting firm to come up with
a tourism slogan and for $150,000 they
came up with visit Scotland. [laughter]
>> It's true. Google it.
>> Well, that's the consulting class for
you.
>> Yeah. So, anyway, um
they came up with InQel. InQel's very
first investment was not a lot. It was
like I I I can't remember if it's a
million and a half. I think it's a
million and a half to [snorts] Palunteer
>> in like 03, something like that.
>> 02. Yeah.
>> And um and now Palunteer is a trillion
dollar company that makes most of its
money contracting with the CIA. It's
publicly traded company and everybody
listen I subscribe to Barrens every
week. It's like buy Palunteer, buy
Palunteer, buy Palunteer.
>> What do you think of their capabilities
and
what they're trying to do just right
now?
>> The agency?
>> No. Palunteer,
>> which is the agency.
>> Yeah, which kind of is the agency. You
know, I I worry very much about about
it's even too weak to say encroachment
on our civil liberties. the I I worry
about the violation of our civil
liberties very much.
>> It is against the law for the CIA to spy
on Americans. Period.
>> Period.
>> That's it. It's against the law. But
they do every day. It's against the law
and it's actually a part of NSA's
charter that they cannot spy on
Americans. You cannot intercept the
communications of Americans. And that's
practically all they do, right? where
they had to build this new facility out
in Utah in the desert that can hold
every phone call, every text message,
every email from every American for the
next 500 years.
>> 500 years.
>> 500 years. How about this? Even the FBI
no longer has to get a warrant
um to take your communications,
right? The metadata from your
communications is for sale. All they
have to do is call T-Mobile and say,
"Hey, uh, I want Julian Dory's uh,
communications. Here's the five grand
that you charge."
>> That's the thing. What Palanteer does is
a whole another level. And I want to
stay with that for a second. But I've
had Mike Yaggley, who I mentioned
earlier, sitting in this chair twice in
the past two months. And the way that he
got back in the crosshairs of the
government where they went, "What the
fuck?" was he was working on
amalgamating marketing data and he
realized what you could just buy
publicly legally. And so he bought a
bunch of data in North Carolina around
Fort Bragg and tracked a bunch of phones
leaving Fort Bragg going to a
neighborhood about 45 minutes away that
was a little bit higher income, meaning
these are most likely special forces.
track down the names of everyone who
lived there, where they went, what they
did, realized they were special forces,
then watched them and charted them, go
across to Syria once every other month
for 5 days to Leafar's concrete company
or Lefar concrete company where which
was obviously a cover for some
undercover operation they were doing.
Yeah. And he went to the government and
showed them and he said, "I did this in
my bedroom.
>> What do you think China's doing?"
Jason Leupold, who is a an investigative
journalist for Bloomberg, formerly of
Vice, BuzzFeed, the LA Times, absolutely
brilliant journalist.
>> He was once called a Foya terrorist by
the uh Pentagon spokesman because he has
filed more FOYA requests than any other
person in American history. He broke the
Hillary Clinton email story just by
>> sending in a FOYA request. Well, he
he revealed the location of the CIA's
secret um drone surveillance base in
Baluchistan, Pakistan. And you know how
he did it? He read somewhere that drones
use a certain kind of aviation fuel. And
so he just did a Freedom of Information
Act request to the Pentagon for uh the
locations of of all of the um deliveries
of this aviation fuel. And like millions
of dollars of fuel were going into this,
you know, desert base in southwestern
Pakistan, this top secret base that's
not top secret anymore because the
Freedom of Information Act has told us
so.
For all the smart guys in government who
are supposed to keep a secret and claim
to be able to keep the secret and
whatever, they literally write stuff in
the modern metadata that someone at home
can get.
>> That's it.
>> That's right.
>> That's why it gets hard to certain
secrets.
>> I wonder
>> it gets hard to believe that they
wouldn't be able to be uncovered in some
ways. And that gets to some of the
weirdest [__] if you start to think
about it. Yeah.
>> But we got we got off we're talking
about the regular public metadata right
here. But Palanteer themselves, I mean,
that's a whole another level.
>> Yeah. So what kinds of things right now
are you most concerned about with what
they're doing?
>> You know, we we don't really know a lot
of what Palanteer does. Most of it is
classified and even then it's classified
at the top secret level because it
involves technology. And we know that
they have massive
uh contracts with uh the CIA. And it's
not just the CIA. They work with DARPA.
They work with the Pentagon at large.
They work with NSA. They're all over
government now. They didn't even exist
20 years ago practically.
>> That's a Peter Teal company, too.
>> Yeah.
>> Very powerful guy.
>> Very powerful.
>> What do What do you think of the Alex
Karp guy who runs it?
>> You know, I did a little
I was I was hired by an interest group
to do a little biographical
mockup of the two of them. And they're
exactly the kind of guys that the CIA
would want to be
>> doing business with. They're um
conservatives.
They are religious.
Um they are extremely patriotic but
driven by profit.
>> And they'll do as they're told and
they'll keep their mouth shut.
>> Karp is is militarily industrially
conservative, but he's technically a
Democrat, right?
>> Yeah. I think he never switched his
party affiliation. Yeah. He's like a
little hard to put in a box with some
things, but
>> and he has said that in interviews where
>> party politics don't hold any interest
for him,
>> right?
>> Yeah. It's tough
>> when you start talking about surveilling
citizens though at like a protest you
don't like or something like that
>> with drones the size of a of a bumblebee
or or a wasp. Yeah.
>> So no one can even see it.
>> Yeah.
>> We're getting to the birds aren't real
territory.
>> Very much. Very much. Yes, we are.
Yes. It's frightening.
>> What about when they're a a company that
is contracted by CIA and for all intents
and purposes created by CIA sense that
they funded them? How about them working
on other conflicts around the world
though? Isn't that like a conflict of
interest?
>> Four other countries.
>> Yes,
>> I would say it is. But they would
probably argue that they've stovepiped
everything and that there's no
crossover. that if they're working on a
CIA project, it's just these people in
this box working on a CIA project. If
they have an MI6 project, it's over here
and never the two shall meet. But what
about Arais Corporation? Here's here's
another one. So,
right around the time that I came home
from Athens in 2000, there was a kind of
a wave of senior level um retirements.
And these were all pretty important
guys, you know, the head of European
operations, the head of near east
operations, the head of domestic
operations, whatever. And um
they decided to just create an LLC where
they could go, you know, smoke cigars
and drink coffee and hang out and play
peuckle all day and uh take a tax
deduction. [snorts]
And so you got to show
you got to show
a gain in two out of five years in order
to keep your LLC.
So they put in for a couple what they
call butts and seats uh contracts where
you just take anybody who's got a
security clearance, put them in these
seats, let them do data entry for six
months, and then the contract's over and
they all get fired. They all have 1099s
anyway, so you don't care.
Well, now they're like a, you know, 20
billion dollar company because
at headquarters, I remember this
happening at the time. They're like,
"Oh, we we have a real need for XYZ."
And somebody says, "What about Jack?
Jack's got this Abraasis thing now.
>> We know everybody. They're all friends
of ours.
>> Greatest shell company of all time."
>> And then there you go.
>> Yeah.
>> And it was taken over once, twice, three
times. It changed its name a couple
times. I think it's still known as a
brais based in Tyson's Corner, Virginia.
These guys never expected to be
billionaires. They were just looking for
a tax deduction on their coffee and
cigars.
>> Oh, that's the definition of finding
money. It's like, oh, there it is. There
it is. I might as well take it.
[laughter]
>> But like back to Palunteer though,
they're So you would imagine they're
compartmentalizing for different
countries.
Doesn't it get weird though when you
have an organization that has intel
about every one of these countries
individually themselves that allegedly
they're not passing back the CIA
>> especially when the conventional wisdom
is that this is a CIA company?
>> Yeah. Like wouldn't doesn't that feel a
little bit like it could be the start of
a 1984 novel? I would guess
that,
okay, if they're working for the Brits,
the Australians, the Canadians, the New
Zealanders, we don't care.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Because Five Eyes, we're all
sharing everything anyway.
>> Okay.
>> But let's say they're working for the
French, the Germans,
whatever. The Hungarians, who knows? I
don't know. Um, I am gonna say that an
officer from the CIA's
um, National Resources Division, those
CIA officers around the United States,
the National Resources Division was
created just so when a corporate CEO or
other officer went to a denied area, say
he went to Moscow for a meeting or
Beijing for a meeting, somebody from the
NR division would go and say, "Hey, you
know, I'm from the CIA. you're a
patriot. Can I ask you some questions
about your trip? They always always say
yes
>> because they're patriots. I would guess
that with Palunteer,
they there are regular routine meetings
within our division
saying, "Ah, you know, I was in uh the
United Arab Emirates the other day and I
ran into soand so and this is what he's
interested in." And you know, something
like that.
>> Yeah, that one just scares me. I don't
know. It's also like the guy, you did
the biography on him, but the guys who
are in charge just seem a little [sighs]
>> Teal and Karp when they talk, they seem
a little divorced from reality,
particularly of the everyman, to be
clear.
>> I think that's how starts.
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> Totally agree.
>> Look at Elon Musk. You know
>> what about Elon
>> I mean he's not the same Elon Musk from
10 or 20 years ago.
>> I told you my my Elon Musk story.
>> Yeah. back at when you met him at the
across the street from the White House
at the hotel
>> Adam's hotel.
>> When you say he's not the same guy like
just normal personality changes or
>> I think it's a combination of things.
You know, he just signed a $1 trillion
contract with Tesla. He's going to have
to make a bunch of a bunch of targets to
uh to collect that money. But
>> it's no longer about
the technology. It's no longer about,
for example, when is the last time you
heard him talk about colonizing Mars?
Time was you couldn't get him to shut up
about colonizing Mars. What about the
high-speed vacuum tube that we were
supposed to go from from LA to San
Francisco in 45 minutes? What happened
to that,
>> John? Men, I when I saw that trillion
dollar deal, I had a thought that I was
like, damn, I should have had this
thought [__] 15 years ago. Like when
you look at the math because it was
already true then, but men are becoming
countries.
>> Yes,
>> he's a country.
>> Yeah,
>> it's about to be worth a trillion
dollars.
>> And you know, if I were Elon Musk, I
would worry about,
you know, an eat the rich movement.
>> Of course,
>> I I really would. I would worry for my
own safety.
>> Well, he has positioned himself. I'm not
even saying this is wrong at all. I'm
saying it's just interesting. He's
positioned himself as the man of the
people who saved free speech and is
speaking for the everyman and funded
Trump who represents the everyman and
stuff like that. But you are absolutely
right that who said this the other day?
I want to give them credit, but it's
like it should be the Captain Obvious
point, but they just put it so
beautifully and it's exactly what it is.
They're like the future isn't a division
of left right problems. That's just what
we're looking at right now. It's up
down. It's elite and everyone else. And
when you look at any empire that has
fallen around the world, one of the many
traits of the falling of the empire, and
I would argue it's probably the most
important trait is a severe separation
and disagreement in future and hope as
it pertains to the lower classes and the
elites. And we talked about it earlier
with something else, but you see that
wealth cap divide. This is something
that's happening around the world.
people who are getting so wealthy that
you know chump change of their wealth
could solve world problems and I say
this as someone who is in no way a
socialist or anything like that I I
don't agree with that ideology but
>> you know does a person need a trillion
dollars no the [__] they don't sorry
>> sorry I I don't I'm I don't think I
think it's a slippery slope to say oh
you make that illegal but like you got
to have some self-awareness or something
I don't know give some of it way. I I I
don't know. It's easy for me to sit here
as a guy who's more than Warren Buffett
has famously said that he's leaving his
children literally nothing.
>> Respect that a lot.
>> I do too. Every cent of it goes to
charity.
>> And you know what? If I don't know how
his kids or grandkids feel about that,
but I would imagine if they get older
and wiser, especially like the grandkids
and the ones who are younger, they'll
they'll thank them for that.
>> Yeah, they will.
>> You're not you you don't have any
fulfillment in life when you're just
giving money. Mm-m.
>> I I always in my old career, I I saw
that, you know,
>> the kids that had the trust funds, they
were just dead.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> They were dead.
>> Yeah. And they never really reached any
kind of potential.
>> Nope. They were always living in the
shadow of something that wasn't theirs.
And I felt I actually felt bad for a lot
of them, you know, like they didn't
choose to have that happen,
>> you know?
>> Yeah.
>> But
>> agreed.
>> I I I just think there's something about
the purpose of life that like you make
your own way, whatever that is, you You
know, I do something public. I want to
be the greatest in the world at it. I
will be one day. You know, I'm going to
have kids.
>> Yep.
>> I want them to go do their own [__]
thing. I don't want them to worry about
like what their dad did. And
>> None [clears throat] of my kids, none of
my five kids have any interest in doing
what I did, which I think is wonderful.
And they've all done things completely
different from each other. My oldest is
a bond trader
>> in uh Chicago. My second is an
elementary school music teacher in North
Carolina. My third is getting a degree
in supply chain economics. My fourth
changes her mind, but right now she's
studying engineering. And my fifth is is
in eighth grade.
>> But uh they're all they have completely
different interests, which I think is
the best and the healthiest.
>> And that's and and that you know I just
think that leads to more happiness that
way too. And it's great that you support
that as well. Also, not for nothing, I
wouldn't want to follow in your
footsteps after what they did to you as
well. So, maybe that would be one good
thing come out of it. Right.
>> That's right. That's right.
>> John, it is always a pleasure, man.
We'll do this again.
>> Always enjoy coming here and seeing you.
>> Love talking with you about world
events. You have such a good outlook on
stuff. So, until next time.
>> Good. We'll have everything linked down
below for you. Your ex, your substack,
your new show, all that.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that sounds great.
>> Okay.
>> Great. I look forward to it. Thank All
right, everybody else, you know what it
is. Give it a thought. Get back to me.
Peace. Thank you guys for watching the
episode. If you haven't already, please
hit that subscribe button and smash that
like button on the video. They're both a
huge, huge help. And if you would like
to follow me on Instagram and X, those
links are in my description below.